Macross Frontier: Labyrinth of Time
/人类开始穿越恒星的旅程已经有半个多世纪了。
/It's been over half a century since
humanity began its journey across the stars.
在那期间，我们与许多外星种族接触，包括一些
During that time, we have come into contact
with many alien races, including some
失落已久的星际文明的后裔，被称为亲文化。
descendants of the long lost interstellar
civilization known as the Pro to culture.
为此，无论是在悲伤中还是在欢乐中，都流下了许多眼泪。
Many tears have been shed because
of this, both in grief and in joy.
大家好！\你们都玩得很开心吗？！
Hey everybody!
You all having a good time?!
很抱歉这么说，但……下一首歌将是最后一首。
I'm sorry to say this, but...
this next song will be the last one.
-啊！我们想要更多！\不，啊！我们想要更多！
- Aw! We want more!
这首歌是献给我所珍爱的人的。
This song is for those I hold dear.
我希望你喜欢它。
I hope you like it.
毫无疑问，这些感觉都在我心里
Without a doubt these feelings are within me
无法控制，它们溢出
Unable to be contained, they overflow
当我想起你，我的胸怀就变成了宇宙，
When I think of you, my bosom becomes the universe,
紧握着星星
holding the stars close
我们的日子有限
Our days are limited
自从那重要的一天以来，已经有一段时间了。
It's been
some time since that fateful day.
我们的日子有限
Our days are limited
我决定用他们来爱你
I've decided to spend them loving you
为了结束这场悲惨的战争，
To put an end to that tragic war,
我决定用他们来爱你
I've decided to spend them loving you
谢丽尔用一首感动银河系的歌曲烧毁了她生命中留下的一切。
Sheryl burned what
was left of her life with a song that moved the galaxy.
谢丽尔用一首感动银河系的歌曲燃烧了她生命中剩下的一切。
Sheryl burned what was left of her life
with a song that moved the galaxy.
我开始找到力量了
I'm starting to find the strength
谢丽尔用一首感动银河系的歌曲烧毁了她生命中留下的一切。
Sheryl burned what
was left of her life with a song that moved the galaxy.
我开始找到力量了
I'm starting to find the strength
直到今天，她仍然在睡觉。
To this day, she still sleeps.
我开始找到力量了
I'm starting to find the strength
说我爱你
to say I love you
这条路很长
It's a long road
由远处的光线指引
Guided by the light
shining in the distance
让我们永远再见面
Let us always meet again
兰卡？
Ranka?
…现在可以见面了
...able to meet now
这种感觉越来越深，
This feeling that grows ever deep,
呵呵？！折叠波浪？！
Huh?! Fold Waves?!
我发誓要坚持
I vow to keep
-嘘！
- Shush!
愿它永不动摇
May it never waver
在寒风中
amidst the freezing wind
银河遗产局已经批准我们进行调查。
The Galactic Heritage Bureau has
given clearance for us to investigate.
谢谢大家一直以来的帮助。
Thanks for always
helping out, everyone.
检查丢失的技术也是超级维度旅行护送员的工作。
Checking out lost technology is also
the job of Super Dimensional Tour escorts.
此外，我们还可以去听你的音乐会。
Plus we get to go to your concerts.
不过，这个地方真是太棒了。
This place is really amazing though.
灵魂之井是Pro to文化的后裔留下的一座庙宇。
The Well of Souls is a temple left behind
by the descendants of the Pro to culture.
灵魂之井。。。
The Well of Souls...
一个与神交流的地方。
A place to commune with the gods.
传说它也被用来和死者交谈。
Legend says it was used to
converse with the dead as well.
请快点，Ranka。
Please make this quick, Ranka.
你还有新歌歌词要完成。
You still have new song lyrics to finish.
明天我们将前往您的下一个旅游站。
And we leave for your
next tour stop tomorrow.
对不起，让你担心。。。
Sorry for worrying you...
但我觉得这次我可能会联系到他。
But I feel that I might
reach him this time.
干得好。太烧和金枪鱼面包，您的最爱。
Here you go. Taiyaki and
tuna buns, your favorites.
此设置每次看起来都像一个
grave站点。
This setup looks like a
grave site every time.
嘿别那么说。
Hey! Don't say that.
这是正确的。阿尔托答应他会活着回来，所以就在那里。
That's right. Alto promised
he'd come back alive, so there.
那是什么？
What was that?
折叠波浪！
Fold Waves!
正如我所想。它必须重新激活以响应
Just as I thought. It must have
reactivated in response to
昨晚音乐会上兰卡的声音。
Ranka's voice during last night's concert.
它在呼唤我。。。
It's calling me...
嗯？
Huh?
是阿尔托打来的！
It's Alto who's calling!
等待太危险了！
Wait! It's too dangerous!
这就是神秘的时间迷宫，
This is the mysterious Labyrinth of Time,
在那里，隐藏的记忆被唤醒
where hidden memories are awakened
兰卡！
Ranka!
我为什么在这里？为什么是我？
Why am I here? Why me?
空洞的回答在我周围舞动
Empty answers dance all around me
即使只是一场梦，我也不在乎
Even if it's just a dream, I don't care
如果这意味着我可以改变过去，
If it means I can change the past,
我自己也会变成魔鬼
I'd become the Devil himself
兰卡！
Ranka!
我还记得那天
I still remember the day
你和我第一次见面
you and I first met
-嗯？
-中音？
- Huh?
- Alto?
真的是他吗？
it really him?
那天的风感觉有点温和。
The wind felt kind of gentle that day.
不，这只是她的回忆。
No, it's just her projected memories.
我从Ranka的大脑中得到了强有力的数据，
I'm getting strong readings from both Ranka's brain,
（我有一种感觉……）
(I had a feeling...)
还有她腹部的折叠细菌。
and the Fold Bacteria in her abdomen.
她的腹部有折叠细菌。
And the Fold Bacteria
in her abdomen.
你觉得很熟悉，虽然我们只见过她腹部的折叠细菌。
You felt so familiar, though we only just
met and the Fold Bacteria in her abdomen.
你觉得很熟悉，虽然我们只是刚刚见面
You felt so familiar, though we only just met
我有一种有趣的感觉
And I had a funny feeling that
也许你对我也有同样的感觉
maybe you felt the same way about me
从那天起，每天都很有趣
From that day on, every day was so much fun
如此悲伤
and so sad
只是有点孤独
And just a little bit lonely
我被这些感觉淹没了
I was overwhelmed by all those feelings
一想到你的名字我就不知所措
I was overwhelmed at the thought of your name
025-8和SO4
025-8 and SO4
你能听到我的声音吗？
Can you hear this voice of mine?
你好，Ranka？
Hello, Ranka?
我想让你给我看更多
I want you to show me more
这是怎么一回事？\现在很晚了。
What is it?
It's pretty late.
这是怎么一回事？\现在很晚了。
What is it?
It's pretty late.
关于各种星星
About all sorts of stars
关于各种各样的明星
关于各种各样的你
About all sorts of you
哦，所以你睡不着。
Oh, so you can't sleep.
025-8和SO4
025-8 and SO4
那么，你能看到东方的天空吗？
Well then, can
you see towards the eastern sky?
那么，你能看到东方天空吗？
Well then, can you see
towards the eastern sky?
你听到我的声音了吗？
Is my voice reaching you?
没错，把灯关掉。
That's right, turn off the lights.
我想让你告诉我更多
I want you to tell me more
关于各种各样的明星
About all sorts of stars
关于各种歌曲
About all sorts of songs
谢丽尔！
Sheryl!
拜托，阿尔托！回应
Please, Alto! Respond!
请快点回来。。。
Please, hurry back...
…为了谢丽尔！
...for Sheryl!
你需要叫醒谢丽尔！
You need to wake Sheryl!
我们走了不同的路，但做了同样的梦
We traveled separate paths,
but dreamed the same dream
这就是为什么我并不孤单
That's why I wasn't alone
自从我失去了你，我到处都能感觉到你的存在
Since I lost you,
I feel your presence everywhere
你的形象，你头发的气味
The image of you, the scent of your hair
从那天起，每一天都是如此美好
From that day on, every day was so beautiful
太令人兴奋了
and so exciting
只是有点孤独
And just a little bit lonely
因为只有当我和你在一起的时候
Because only when I'm with you
星星会发光吗，
do the stars shine bright,
哇…嘿，大家都在看。
Whoa... Hey, everyone's watching.
大海变深了，
The seas go deep,
天空高耸入云
And the skies reach high
021-5和FO9
021-5 and FO9
你能听到我的声音吗？
Can you hear this voice of mine?
我想让你给我看更多
I want you to show me more
关于各种各样的明星
About all sorts of stars
关于各种各样的你
About all sorts of you
021-5和FO9
021-5 and FO9
你听到我的声音了吗？
Is my voice reaching you?
我想让你告诉我更多
I want you to tell me more
关于各种各样的明星
About all sorts of stars
关于各种歌曲
About all sorts of songs
你现在觉得我怎么样？
What do you think of me now?
我变得更强了吗？
Have I become a stronger person?
我要你温柔地告诉我
I want you to tell me gently
当我是。。。
When I was...
爱上上帝。。。
in love with God...
021-5和FO9
021-5 and FO9
我从没想过。。。
I never expected...
谢丽尔？中音？！
Sheryl? Alto?!
021-5和FO9
021-5 and FO9
你听到我的声音了吗？
ls my voice reaching you?
-0271-5和FO9
-FO9
-0271-5 and FO9
-你听到我的声音了吗？\非FO9
-Is my voice reaching you?
-FO9
我想让你告诉我更多
I want you to tell me more
关于各种各样的明星
About all sorts of stars
真漂亮。。。
So pretty...
关于各种各样的你
About all sorts of you
这么优美的歌曲。
Such a beautiful song.
她找到他了吗？
Did she reach him?
我说不清。
I can't tell.
-当我……N-025-8和SO4
-When I was...
-025-8 and SO4
但废墟上的折叠波仍在增强。
But the Fold Waves from the ruins are still getting stronger.
你听到我的声音了吗？
ls my voice reaching you?
-爱上上帝……我想让你告诉我更多
-In love with God...
-I want you to tell me more
关于各种各样的明星
About all sorts of stars
-025-8和SO4
-（025-8与SO4）
-025-8 and SO4
-(025-8 and SO4)
你听到我的声音了吗？
Is my voice reaching you?
-025-8和SO4
-（025-8与SO4）
-025-8 and SO4
-(025-8 and SO4)
我想让你告诉我更多
I want you to tell me more
-025-8和SO4
-S04
-025-8 and SO4
-你听到我的声音了吗？
-S04号
-Is my voice reaching you?
-S04
我想保持这种感觉
I want to hold on to this feeling
阿尔托？
Alto?
我想保持这种感觉
I want to hold on to this feeling
我现在和你在一起
That I'm with you right now
-025-8和SO4
-S04
-025-8 and SO4
-你听到我的声音了吗？
-联系您
-Is my voice reaching you?
-Reaching you
我想保持这种感觉
I want to hold on to this feeling
阿尔托！
Alto!
我现在和你在一起
That I'm with you right now
-我现在就和你在一起
-（我现在就跟你在一起）
-That I'm with you right now
-(That I'm with you right now)
-我现在就和你在一起
-（我现在就跟你在一起）
-That I'm with you right now
-(That I'm with you right now)
这是放大的
倍波传输！
It's an amplified
Fold Wave transmission!
那是…他吗？
Is that... him?
在光的尽头。。。
At the end of the light...
这次我不会失去你。
I'm not losing you this time.
明亮的眼睛，陷入黑暗
Shining eyes, fall into the dark side
我不能再回去了
I can't go back again
破败之路
THE PATH OF RUIN
Sv-303待命启动。
Sv-303 Standby to launch.
一个世界经历了这一切
A world played out through this
导向装置全部连接。
Guide units all connected.
一个世界经历了这一切
A world played out through this
空间压缩推力放大系统标称值。
Spatial compression thrust amplification system nominal.
月光引导旋律空间压缩
推力放大系统标称。
Moonlight guided melody Spatial compression
thrust amplification system nominal.
月光引导旋律
Moonlight guided melody
QFV反应子弹组已完成。
QFV reaction bullet set completed.
等着看吧
Wait to see
发生了什么事
What's going on QUIETLY
多维折叠石英系统平稳同步。
Multidimensional Fold Quartz System synchronizing smoothly.
破坏的调子是。。。
THE TUNE OF DESTRUCTION IS...
所以不要回头看
So don't look back
埋伏等待革命的机会
Lying in wait for a chance at revolution
走进你，
Into you,
现在还没有出路
there ls no way out NOT YET
等待时间
Wait for the time
静静地醒来
of awakening quietly, quietly
必须准备好摇滚
Gotta be ready to rock
也许…只有你能，只有你能
Maybe... Only you can, only you can
摇晃我
rock me
我知道你可以，我知道你能
I know you can, I know you can
我知道你可以，我知道你能空间扭曲率增加。接近维度断层。
I know you can, I know you can Space distortion
rate increasing. Approaching Dimensional Fault.
空间失真率增加。
接近尺寸故障。
Space distortion rate increasing.
Approaching Dimensional Fault.
只有你能，只有你能
Only you can, only you can
摇晃我
rock me
警报器系统在操作参数范围内运行。
Siren System operating
within operational parameters.
走向黑暗，走向黑暗
To the darkness, to the darkness
准备好摇滚，准备好摇滚！
Ready to rock, get ready to rock!
好的现在，你的声音将打开通往新时代的大门，
Good. Now, thy voice shall open
the gates to a new era,
倒计时到毁灭，是的/
Countdown to ruin, YES/
哦，伟大的黑暗歌手。
o' great Singer of the Dark.
准备好摇滚，准备好摇滚！
Ready to rock, get ready to rock!
立即释放它
Unleash it now
准备好摇滚了
Gonna be ready to rock
进入你的内心
Into you
准备好摇滚了
Gonna be ready to rock
准备好了，准备好了！
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock!
Macross Delta: ZETTAI LIVE!!!!
在过去的五十年里，
Windermere
For the past five decades,
Windermere has been in
与地球人类持续不断的激烈冲突。
constant bitter conflict
with the humans of Earth.
对我们来说，
To us,
这是一场夺回天空自由的圣战。
it was a holy war to reclaim
the freedom of our skies.
但即便如此，太多的翅膀和
But even so, too many wings and
失去了太多宝贵的生命。
too many precious lives have been lost.
让我们祈祷死者的灵魂
Let us pray that the souls of the departed
被风带到喷泉之风，让他们可以安息。
be borne by the wind to the Fountain
of Wind so that they may rest in peace.
我们目前正在与联合国政府谈判一项和平条约，
We are currently negotiating a peace
treaty with the U.N. Government,
如果我尝试，我会飞。如果我试试，我就能飞了。如果我尝试，我会飞。
If I try, I can fly. If I try,
I can fly. If I try, I can fly.
-如果我尝试-
-Fre-Fre！
- If I try—
- Fre-Fre!
来吧，放松点。
Come on, loosen up.
Freyja，紧张到极点。
Freyja, tense to the max.
这是她逃跑后第一次回来
Well, this ls her first time
back since running away
来自她的村庄，加上她的国王举办了一场音乐会来庆祝休战。
from her village, plus it's a concert
held by her king to celebrate the truce.
振作起来，不要落后！
Get it together
or be left behind!
好吧！
Alrighty!
献给神圣羽毛下的风之子，
To the Children of the Wind
united under the sacred feather,
我发誓要让和平之风席卷整个银河系。
I vow to make the winds of
peace sweep throughout the galaxy.
以大风的名义！
In the name of the Great Wind!
向上爆炸/
Upward Bomb Burst/
准备好迎接挑战了吗，红骑士？
Up for the challenge, Crimson Knight?
嘿，你这个无聊的白痴！
Heh, you dull-winded oaf!
去
Go!
什么
What?!
去
Go!
感觉很好！
Feelin' good!
哇！他正在跳伊梅尔曼舞/
Whoa! He's doin'
the Immelmann dance/
海亚特，回到队形！
Hayate, get back in formation!
放松点，幻影，只要我们能搞定结局，演出就会很好-
fine as long as we nail the finale—
Relax Mirage, the show will be
-该死的你！
-什么/
- Damn you!
- What?/
你敢在陛下面前行动吗？！
You dare act out in the
presence of His Majesty?!
这只是一点服务！
It's just a bit of service!
不需要您的服务！
Your service isn't needed!
还是个男孩。
Still just a boy.
-深红骑士！回来
-抓住他，博格爵士！
- Crimson Knight! Come back!
- Get him, Sir Bogue!
啊……深红骑士的\有些动作。
Ah... Crimson Knight's
got some moves.
你那家伙的舞也不错。
Your guy's dance
isn't bad either.
再见，深红骑士！
See ya later, Crimson Knight!
嘿什么。。。！
Hey! What the...!
音乐就是爱！
Music is Love!
音乐是希望！
Music is Hope!
音乐就是生活！
Music is Life!
音乐是神秘的！
Music is Mystery!
音乐就是能量！
Music is Energy!
听女神的歌！
Listen to the songs of goddesses!
超维度金星，Walkiure！
Super Dimension Venus, Walkiure!
在游荡的冰川里
In the wandering glacier
隐藏的秘密
a secret lies hidden
由于一次奇怪的意外
By a freak accident
发生了一次邂逅。所以限制
an encounter happened. So restricting
从混乱的深处涌上来
Welling up from the depths of chaos
深冻结显示了它的108个面
the deep freeze shows its 108 facets
嘴唇好烫
Lips so hot
它们似乎融化了
that they seem to melt
完全熔化，形成
Complete meltdown, it forms
我不知道。只是重复
I don't know. Just repeating
这种冲动，
this urge,
让它出来。。。
letting it out...
纯洁的雪花触摸着我的手
as他们相互吸引
Pure falling snow touches my hand
as they attract each other
我的感觉被唤醒了，头晕目眩
My feelings become aroused, so dizzy
没有多余的生命，你和我，到了极限
No spare lives, you and me, to the limit
请接受它，
Please accept it,
这个吻，现在
this kiss, right now
看，白银世界又回来了
See, the silver world returns
微弱闪烁的寂静之声
The sound of silence that glimmered faintly
释放所有压抑的情绪，
Unleash all the pent-up emotions,
-唱歌
-Sing
唱
Sing
! 坠入爱河，在这个无限的星系
! fell in love, in this infinite galaxy
这些情感从我心中涌出，如此脱节
These feelings spilling out of me
are so disjointed
它们是没有恶意的本能，所以它们是重叠的
They are instinct without malice,
so they overlap
暂时不要从我这里拿走它们
Don't take them from me just yet
纯洁的雪花触摸着我的手
as他们相互吸引
Pure falling snow touches my hand
as they attract each other
我的感觉被唤醒了，头晕目眩
My feelings become aroused, so dizzy
没有多余的生命，你和我，到了极限
No spare lives, you and me, to the limit
请接受它，
Please accept it,
这个吻，现在
this kiss, right now
-Walkure！步行！
-步行！
- Walkure!
-弗雷亚！
-苹果女孩！
- Freyja!
- Apple Girl!
谢谢大家！
Thank you everybody!
Freyja的符文太亮了！
Freyja's rune is so bright!
多么耀眼的风啊，符文如此宜人。
What a dazzling wind,
so pleasant to the rune.
我希望Roid和Keith
I wish both Roid and Keith
我们是来感受这风的。
were here to feel this wind.
唷…嗯？
Whew... Huh?
弗雷亚？
Freyja?
这些房子很漂亮。
These houses are delightful.
他们真可爱！
They're so cute!
如此宁静。太激动了。
So serene. So excited.
是 啊真的很好，弗雷娅。。。
Yeah. It's really nice, Freyja...
嘿，怎么了？
Hey, what's wrong?
弗雷娅跑掉了，保释了她的订婚。
Freyja ran off, bailed on her engagement.
丽丽！
Rei-Rei!
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
市长先生！
Mister Mayor!
我真的真的…我真的很抱歉！
I'm really, really...
I'm so totally sorry!
看到你没事，我很欣慰，弗雷娅。
It's a relief to see you're okay, Freyja.
嗯？
Huh?
谢谢你照顾Freyja。
Thank you for taking care of Freyja.
我代表NRavengrass村的人鞠躬我的符文。
On behalf of the people of
Ravengrass Village, I bow my rune.
市长先生。
Mister Mayor.
不，是Freyja的声音
No, it was Freyja's voice
弥合了温德梅尔和我们之间的鸿沟。
that bridged the gap between
Windermere and ourselves.
-弗雷亚！
-Freyja！
- Freyja!
欢迎回来！
Welcome back!
-已经很久了。
-符文派卡！
- It's been so long.
- Rune Pika!
好了，伙计们，轮到你们了。
Alright guys, wait your turn.
M-Muah！干得好！
M-Muah! Here you go!
Gori Gori可爱！
Gori-Gori cute!
十连胜！
Ten win streak!
嘿，又弱又弱。
Heh, weak and feeble.
我是一个没有怜悯心的女人。
I'm a woman without mercy.
你曾与兰卡·李、超级维度灰姑娘一起表演过？！
You've performed with Ranka Lee,
the Super Dimensional Cinderella?!
啊，是的。我曾经是个独唱偶像，所以。。。
Ah, yes. I used to be a solo idol, so...
我不会说你和她一起“表演”。
I wouldn't say you "performed with" her.
那是一个综艺节目，她在那里观看了你的视频
It was a variety show where
she watched a video of you
银河河马竞技表演\在录音室录制期间，仅此而已。
rodeo riding a Galactic Hippo
during a studio taping, that's all.
G-银河河马？
G-Galactic Hippo?
嗯，就是这样吗？
I真的想不起来了…嗯？！
Hmm, was that what it was?
I can't really recall... Huh?!
-哇。
-Kaname，尴尬的过去。
- Wow.
- Kaname, embarrassing past.
住手！
Cut it out!
起泡苹果酒？不，谢谢。
Sparkling apple cider? No thanks.
为什么不呢？它很好吃。
Why not? It's tasty.
她一直在喝苹果牛奶。
All she's been drinking is apple milk.
我知道！她处理不了这些问题。
I know! She can't handle the fizzles.
真是个婴儿！
What a baby!
我得说，我们村的Napples是Gori Gori很棒！
I gotta say, our village's
apples are Gori-Gori great!
对吧，海亚特？
Right, Hayate?
是的，戈里·戈里肯定。
Yeah, Gori-Gori for sure.
等等，你是Freyja的男朋友吗？！
Wait, are you
Freyja's boyfriend?!
真正地但他不是地球人吗？
Really? But isn't he an Earthling?
W-什么。。。？
W-Wha...?
不，我和海亚特不是那样的。。。！
No, me and Hayate aren't like that...!
那么地球上的风是什么味道呢？
So what's an Earthling's wind taste like?
妻子一直在谈论想要孩子。
Wife's been talking about wanting kids.
嗯，越快越好。
Well, the sooner the better.
然后是第二个和第三个。
Then it's on to the second and third one.
这是怎么一回事？
What is it?
哦，只是。。。
Oh, it's just...
这里的每个人都很年轻。。。
Everyone here really is so young...
混血儿的平均寿命为30年。
The average lifespan of a
Windermerian is 30 years.
围绕这些部分，
Around these parts,
孩子五岁时就种下自己的树苗。
a child plants their own
sapling at the age of five.
记住，这个星球上的人们与我们截然不同。
Remember, the people of this planet
are very different from us.
市长先生。
Mister Mayor.
谢谢你，先生，
Thank you sir,
欢迎Freyja像这样回家。
for welcoming Freyja home like this.
-同样，看到Freyja如此高兴-
-背叛是死罪。
- Likewise, seeing Freyja so happ—
- Defection is a capital offense.
感谢海因茨陛下的仁慈。
Be thankful for His Majesty Heinz's mercy.
是的，我完全理解。
Yes, I fully understand.
你为什么提起这个？
Freyja歌唱带来和平！
Why're you bringing that up?
Freyja sang to bring peace!
你在这方面没有发言权，局外人。
You have no say in this, outsider.
你说什么？！
What did you say?!
嘿，你们怎么了？！
Hey, what's with you guys?!
退后！
Back off!
别胡说了！
Stop this nonsense!
派对结束了！
Party's over!
在这一点上与客户交谈有什么用？！
What use is talking to
aliens at this point?!
我们应该把他们赶出去！
We should be running them out!
根据陛下的命令，我的任务是保护你。
By order of His Majesty,
I'm tasked to protect you.
即使我和那些人完全在一起。
Even though I completely
agree with those men.
-什么？！
-保持住。让他来处理这件事。
- What?!
- Hold it. Let him handle this.
你扰乱了和平。
You're disturbing the peace.
骑士爵士！
Sir Knight!
去死吧Walkire！
To hell with Walkire!
他们在我们的风中喷出他们肮脏的歌曲！
They're spewing their
filthy songs in our wind!
不管你喜不喜欢，他们都是女王陛下的客人。
Like it or not, they are
His Majesty's guests.
你的意思是反对你的国王吗？
Do you mean to oppose your king?
请稍等。
Just a moment please.
-约翰神父？
-约翰神父！
- Father Johann?
- Father Johann!
约翰神父！
Father Johann!
约翰神父？
Father Johann?
约翰·温利（Johann Winly）。
Johann Winly.
供奉风之神的祭司之一。
One of the priests who
serve the God of the Wind.
拜托，你能原谅这些人的冒犯吗？
Please, could you possibly forgive
these men for their offense?
约翰神父。。。
Father Johann...
如你所愿。
As you wish.
谢谢你。
You have my thanks.
你们三个现在该走了。
You three should leave for now.
W-我们会的。
W-We will.
谢谢你，约翰神父。
Thank you, Father Johann.
我希望你能原谅我的打扰。
I hope you will forgive my intrusion.
不，你真的救了我们。
No, you really saved us.
所以你是Mikumo Guynemer，明星之星。
So you are Mikumo Guynemer,
Singer of the Stars.
我是Walkdure的Mikumo Guynemer，
I am Mikumo Guynemer of Walkdure,
再也没有了。
nothing more.
是的，当然。请原谅我。
Yes, of course. Do forgive me.
弗雷娅·维恩。
Freyja Wion.
昨天是我最近第一次听到你唱歌。
Yesterday was the first time
I've heard you sing in a while.
我记得每次我访问这个村庄时都受到你们的歌曲的欢迎。
I remember being welcomed by your
songs every time I visited this village.
我希望你继续为风添加你的美妙声音。
I hope you continue to add
your fine voice to the wind.
你，你说对了！
Y-You betcha!
弗雷亚！你的礼貌在哪里？\没有办法和约翰神父说话！
Freyja! Where are your manners?
That's no way to talk to Father Johann!
哦
Oh!
哦，我错过了这里的风的颜色。
Oh, I missed the color of the wind here.
到春天末，这个地方将盛开苹果花。
By the end of Spring, this place will
be blooming with apple blossoms.
到处都是白色的小花！
Little white flowers everywhere!
我真的很想给你看，海亚特。
I'd really like to show you, Hayate.
是的，我希望有一天能看到它。
Yeah, I'd like to see it someday.
你从哪里弄到这样一张旧照片的？\这太可爱了。他们俩独自一人在果园里。
Where did you get an old picture like that anyway?
That's so cute. The two of them off alone in the orchard.
真可爱。他们俩独自一人在果园里。
That's so cute. The two of
them off alone in the orchard.
我是一个没有限制的女人。真可爱。\他们俩独自一人在果园里。
I am a woman without limits. That's so cute.
The two of them off alone in the orchard.
我是一个没有限制的女人。
I am a woman without limits.
我是一个没有限制的女人？
Hmm?
还有什么事困扰着你吗？
Something else bothering you?
这是不可能的配对，混血儿和地球人。
It's an impossible pairing,
Windermerians and Earthlings.
你怎么能这么肯定？
How can you be so certain?
我的家人被地球人杀害了。
My family was killed by Earthlings.
我们村也知道战争。事实上
Our village has known war as
well. And there's the fact that
我们的寿命与地球人的寿命不同。
our life span is different
than that of Earthlings.
说实话，村民们都很担心
To tell the truth, the
villagers are all worried
总有一天，这会给你们和Freyja带来悲伤。
that one day this will bring
sorrow to you folks and Freyja.
即便如此，总有一天，所有的风都会合而为一。
Even so, one day all winds will be as one.
找到了！
Found it!
我回来了。
I'm home.
这就是你的树，弗雷娅？
So this is your tree, Freyja?
不，它是我奶奶的。
No, it's my grandma's.
我从没见过她，但这棵树
I never met her, but this tree
是这里最古老的，苹果味道最好。
is the oldest one here,
with the best-tasting apples.
太好了！
It's so good!
正当
Right?
然后你周围的小树就是我种的。
And then the smaller trees
around you are the ones I planted.
哦
Oh.
山顶上的那个是我妈妈的，
The one atop that hill is my mom's,
后面那个是我爸爸的。
and the one back there is my dad's.
我妈妈变得随风而动
My mom became one with the wind
当我三岁的时候，我爸爸刚刚结束了上次战争。
when I was three, and my dad
just after the last war.
我懂了。
I see.
我想我父亲去世时我大约十岁。
I think I was about ten
when my old man died.
你说他是飞行员。
You said he was a pilot.
我也跟你说过阿拉德司令，对吧？
I told you about Commander Arad too, right?
是的，他是你父亲的下属。
Yes, he was your father's subordinate.
这是正确的。
That's right.
当我不知道该怎么办的时候，他招募我当飞行员。
He recruited me to be a pilot when I
didn't know what to do with myself.
我仍然清楚地记得，我的第一次单人飞行。
I still remember it vividly,
my first solo flight.
我当时就感觉到了。。。
I felt it right then...
我和爸爸在一起的感觉。
The feeling that I was with my dad.
他有点古怪。
He was kind of an eccentric guy.
总是从他驻扎的地方发送手写信件，
Always sending hand written letters
from where he was stationed,
每个都有一个随机短语。
each with a single random phrase.
比如什么？
Like what?
这样地。
Like this.
“天空广阔。”
“The sky is vast."
天空是。。。
The sky is...
天空是广阔的！
The sky is vast!
“雨水的味道。”
"Scent of the rain."
“星星充满了夜晚。”
"Stars fill the night."
一个仍然是绿色的水果就是一个
A fruit still green is one
被吸引是二
Being attracted is two
我的心在燃烧
My heart is burning
弗雷亚。。。
Freyja...
一个承诺就是三个
A promise is three
被拔毛是四个
Being plucked is four
穿越天涯海角
Traveling the sky's end
明星们一定很悲伤
The stars must be sad foo
“云形如山。”
"Clouds shaped like mountains."
第五，眼泪涌上又流下
Five, tears well up and fall
“大海是蓝色的。”
"The sea is blue."
“沙漠很热。”
"The desert is hot."
想念那些逝去的人
Missing those that are gone
“星系很大。”
“The galaxy is huge."
让我们唱一首祈祷歌
Let us sing a song of prayer, that it
到达光明之海的遥远海岸
reaches the far shores of this sea of light
红苹果，小苹果
Red apples, small apples
成熟和变色的快乐
Bits of joy that ripen and change color
让我们一个个数数
Let us count them one by one
看到这些面孔
to see the faces
我爱的人
of those we I love
这是一首流传了好几代的温德曼传奇歌曲。
That was a Windermerian song of legend,
passed down for generations.
这是关于一个乡村女孩和风之神的故事，她从星星的对面而来。
It's about a village girl and the God of
the Wind who came from across the stars.
一首苦乐参半的情歌。
A bittersweet love song.
我爱你，弗雷娅！
I love you, Freyja!
我想一起生活！
I want to live our lives out together!
你知道苹果花十天不开花吗？
Did you know that apple blossoms
only bloom for ten days?
它们绽放，然后立即凋谢。
They burst into bloom,
and fall right away.
你真的同意吗？
Are you really okay with that?
有一朵像我一样的苹果花吗？
With an apple flower like me?
我爱你，不管你是什么样的人！
I love you Freyja, however you are!
谢谢你，海亚特。
Thank you, Hayate.
我也。。。
I also...
什么
What?
明亮的眼睛，陷入黑暗
Shining eyes, fall into the dark side
那是从哪里来的？
Where's that coming from?
风中有扰动。
There's a disturbance in the wind.
紧张，等等，但有点。。。
Tense, so on edge, but it kinda...
我不能再回去了
I can't go back again THE PATH OF RUIN
…听起来像Kumo Kumo。
...Sounds like Kumo-Kumo.
这首歌……可能吗？
This singing... Is it possible?
一个世界经历了这一切
A world played out through this
折叠门？！
A Fold Gate?!
Windermere被维度故障隔离！
Windermere is isolated by a dimensional fault!
月光引导旋律
Moonlight guided melody
直接折叠\不可能在大气中折叠。
Folding directly
into the atmosphere isn't possible.
等着看吧
Wait to see
发生了什么事
what's going on QUIETLY
破坏的调子是……所以不要回头看
THE TUNE OF DESTRUCTION IS...
So don't look back
毁灭的旋律是……所以不要回头看。一艘不明身份的船出现在拉文格拉斯上空。
THE TUNE OF DESTRUCTION IS... So don't look back
An unidentified ship has appeared above Ravengrass.
一艘不明身份的船在拉文格拉斯上空出现。
An unidentified ship has
appeared above Ravengrass.
躺在那里等待革命的机会，一艘经核认证的船出现在Ravengrass上空。
Lying in wait for a chance at revolution An
unidentified ship has appeared above Ravengrass.
埋伏等待革命的机会
Lying in wait for a chance at revolution
躺在床上等待革命的机会
放大图像！
Lying in wait for a chance at revolution
Magnifying image!
埋伏等待革命的机会
Lying in wait for a chance at revolution
到你那里去了，那是……一艘马级轮船？！
Into you,
That's... a Ma cross class ship?!
那是……一艘马跨级船？！
现在还没有出路
那是……马跨级船？！
There ls no way out NOT YET
That's... a Ma cross class ship?!
现在还没有出路
There ls no way out NOT YET
目前还没有出路，它似乎已经被大量修改。
there is no way out NOT YET
It appears to have been heavily modified.
它似乎已经做了大量修改。
等待觉醒的时间
I它似乎已被严重修改。
Wait for the time of awakening
It appears to have been heavily modified.
等待觉醒的时间
Wait for the time of awakening
Unable来识别它的起源。
Unable to identify its origin.
等待觉醒的时间
Wait for the time of awakening
很好地等待觉醒的时间。争夺空中骑士
Very well. Scramble the Aerial Knights
很好。争夺空中骑士
安静，安静，非常好。争夺空中骑士
quietly, quietly
Very well. Scramble the Aerial Knights
安静，安静
quietly, quietly
安静地，安静地
启动Sigur Berrentz！
quietly, quietly
and launch the Sigur Berrentzs!
必须准备好震撼
主反应堆功率输出增加！
Gotta be ready to rock
Main reactor power output increasing!
也许…只有你能，只有你能
Maybe... Only you can, only you can
加入人造重力！
Engaging artificial gravity!
也许…只有你能，只有你能
Maybe... Only you can, only you can
也许……只有你能，只有你能
Sigur Berrentzs乘飞机！
Maybe... Only you can, only you can
Sigur Berrentzs taking flight!
Sigur Berrentz正在飞行！
震撼我
Sigur Berrentzs起飞！
Rock me
Sigur Berrentzs taking flight!
Sigur Berrentz正在飞行！
! 我知道你能，我知道你可以乘飞机旅行！
! know you can, I know you can
Sigur Berrentzs taking flight!
! 知道你能，我知道你能
! know you can, I know you can
只有你能，只有你能
Only you can, only you can
摇晃我
rock me
走向黑暗，走向黑暗
To the darkness, to the darkness
准备好摇滚，准备好摇滚！
Ready to rock, get ready to rock!
倒数计时，是的！
Countdown TO RUIN, YES!
准备好摇滚，准备好摇滚！
Ready to rock, get ready to rock!
立即释放它
Unleash it now
准备好摇滚了
Gonna be ready to rock
准备好震撼
未知的敌方部署战斗机！
Gonna be ready to rock
Unknown hostile deploying fighters!
未知敌方部署战斗机！
该死的侵略者！
Damn invaders!
向你们
Damn入侵者！
Into you
Damn invaders!
进入你的内心
Into you
走吧！
Let's go!
准备好摇滚了
Gonna be ready to rock
准备好摇滚这是第三个订单。现在加入您！
This is the 3rd Order. Joining you now!
这是第三个订单。现在加入您！
准备好了，准备好了！
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock!
This is the 3rd Order. Joining you now!
准备好了，准备好了！
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock!
Da！
Da!
准备好了，准备好了！
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock!
准备好了，准备好了！目标\忍无可忍！无法识别？这是一场未知的战斗-
inbound! Unable to identify? It's an unknown fight—
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock! Target
准备好了，准备好了！
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock!
Theo！
Theo!
提奥！
提奥！大家散开！
Theo! Everyone spread out!
-Xao！
-我仍然很好！
- Xao!
- I'm still good!
那么好吧。。。
Alright then...
明白了！
Gotcha!
是的，各位，现在是表演时间。
Yeah everybody, it's showtime.
就在这里，嘿，现在走
RIGHT HERE, hey go now
毁灭，让我们摇滚！岩石
UNTO DESTRUCTION, LET'S Rock! Rock!
是的总是保持冷静，
Yeah ALWAYS just be cool,
是的，总是保持冷静，
它躲过了他们？！
Yeah ALWAYS just be cool,
It dodged them?!
是的总是保持冷静，
Yeah ALWAYS just be cool,
! 知道也许你是对的
! know that maybe you're right
我要…不不不不/
I'm gonna...No No No No/
我要…不，不，不不，不/每个人，在教堂里躲避。
I'm gonna...No No No No/ Everyone,
take shelter inside the church.
所有人，躲在教堂里。
Everyone, take shelter
inside the church.
说吧，说吧，每个人都不要在教堂里避难。
Say na na na na, what you say
Everyone, take shelter inside the church.
说不，说不，你说什么
Say na na na na, what you say
我要把你变成我的，娜！/不！不！钠/
I'm gonna make you mine, Na!/ Na! Na! Na/
我要把你变成我的，娜！/不！不！不！
无论是Eether还是Ragna都无法到达。
I'm gonna make you mine, Na!/ Na! Na! Na!
Can't reach either the Aether or Ragna.
我要把你变成我的，娜！/不！不！钠/
I'm gonna make you mine, Na!/ Na! Na! Na/
我要把你变成我的，娜！/不！不！Na/
T那首歌干扰了所有Fold通信？
I'm gonna make you mine, Na!/ Na! Na! Na/
That song is jamming all Fold communications?
那首歌干扰了所有的旧通讯？
That song is jamming all
Fold communications?
你疯了吗？永远不要让你走那首歌干扰了所有的Fold通讯？
Are you crazy? Never let you go That
song is jamming all Fold communications?
你疯了吗？永远不要让你走
Are you crazy? Never let you go
你明白了，永远不知道，牺牲了
S短程通信仍在工作。
You got it, never know, in sacrifice
Short range comms are still working.
你得到了，永远不知道，牺牲
You got it, never know, in sacrifice
你明白了，永远不知道，我正在远程呼叫Siggies。
I'm calling in the Siggies by remote.
我正在远程呼叫Siggies。
（是的，我知道，我知道）我正在远程呼叫Siggies。
(Yes I know, I know)
I'm calling in the Siggies by remote.
（是的，我知道，我知道）
(Yes I know, I know)
Fold Sound Link按计划过渡。
Fold Sound Link transition on schedule.
按计划折叠声音链接转换。
到底怎么回事？您说得对
按计划完成声音链接转换。
What the hell is going on? You're right
Fold Sound Link transition on schedule.
到底怎么回事？你说得对
What the hell is going on? You're right
太疯狂了，分解它，分解它
So crazy, break it down,
break it down, break it down
你是认真的吗？也许，也许/
Are you serious? Maybe, maybe... Of/
让它成为现实
Just make it a reality
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？
So crazy, crazy, get out! What do you say?
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？\什么？！
What?!
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？
So crazy, crazy, get out! What do you say?
Ugh…什么？
Ugh... What?
啊…什么？
! 知道你想要什么吗？什么？
! know what you want
Ugh... What?
你是唯一的一个，让我更高
You're the only one, take me higher
告诉我，黑暗是什么意思？
Tell me, what's the meaning
of darkness, darkness?
没有出路，让我告诉你
No way out, let me tell you
哦哦给我带路，没有出路，没有出路
Oh! Oh! Show me the way,
oh no way, no way out
哦哦给我带路，不，不，没有出路Freyja！
Oh! Oh! Show me the way,
oh no way, no way out Freyja!
哦哦给我带路，没有出路，没有出路
Oh! Oh! Show me the way,
oh no way, no way out
哦哦给我带路，不，不，没有出路Freyja！
Oh! Oh! Show me the way,
oh no way, no way out Freyja!
这首歌是什么？
What is this song?
它正在影响我们的生物折叠受体！
It's affecting our Bio-Fold Receptors!
新当选的
Incoming!
是的，各位，现在是表演时间。
Yeah everybody, it's showtime.
就在这里，嘿，现在走
RIGHT HERE, hey go now
毁灭，让我们摇滚！岩石
UNTO DESTRUCTION, LET'S Rock! Rock!
是的总是保持冷静，
Yeah ALWAYS just be cool,
! 知道也许你是对的
! know that maybe you're right
我要…不不不不/
I'm gonna...No No No No/
说不，说不，你说什么
Say na na na na, what you say
我要把你变成我的，娜！/不！不！钠/
I'm gonna make you mine, Na!/ Na! Na! Na/
你疯了吗？永远不要让你走
Are you crazy? Never let you go
你得到了，永远不知道，牺牲
You got it, never know, in sacrifice
（是的，我知道，我知道）
(Yes I know, I know)
到底怎么回事？你说得对
What the hell is going on? You're right
太疯狂了，分解它，分解它
So crazy, break it down,
break it down, break it down
如此疯狂，崩溃点燃，崩溃，崩溃？\苹果…！-弗雷亚！
So crazy, break lit down, break it down, break it down?
- The apples...! - Freyja!
你是认真的吗？也许，也许…哦！
苹果！每个人都有苹果！
Are you serious? Maybe, maybe...Oh!
The apples! Everyone's apples!
你是认真的吗？也许，也许…哦！
Are you serious? Maybe, maybe...Oh!
你是认真的吗？也许，也许…哦！\不要！
Don't!
你是认真的吗？也许，也许…哦！
Are you serious? Maybe, maybe...Oh!
你是认真的吗？也许，也许…哦！\不是我爸爸的！我妈妈的！
My dad's! My mom's!
我爸爸的！我妈妈的！
让它成为现实
M我爸爸的！我妈妈的！
Just make it a reality
My dad's! My mom's!
让它成为现实
Just make it a reality
让它成为现实吧
No！他们不能！他们不能！
Just make it a reality
No! They can't! They can't!
不他们不能！他们不能！
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？
不！他们不能！他们不能！
So crazy, crazy, get out! What do you say?
No! They can't! They can't!
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？
So crazy, crazy, get out! What do you say?
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？\抓住自己！
Get a hold of yourself!
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？
So crazy, crazy, get out! What do you say?
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？你认为如果你死在这里，你的父母会很高兴吗？！
So crazy, crazy, get out! What do you say? You think
your mom and dad would be happy if you died here?!
你认为如果你死在这里，你的父母会很高兴吗？！
You think your mom and dad
would be happy if you died here?!
! 知道你想要什么吗？你认为如果你死在这里，你的妈妈和爸爸会很高兴吗？！
! know what you want You think your mom
and dad would be happy if you died here?!
你认为如果你死在这里，你的父母会很高兴吗？！
You think your mom and dad
would be happy if you died here?!
你是唯一的一个，让我更高你认为如果你死在这里，你的父母会很高兴吗？！
You're the only one, take me higher You think
your mom and dad would be happy if you died here?!
你是唯一的一个，让我更高
You're the only one, take me higher
告诉我，黑暗的含义是什么，黑暗？我不会让他们这样做的。
Tell me, what's the meaning of darkness,
darkness? I won't let them do this.
告诉我，黑暗是什么意思？
Tell me, what's the meaning
of darkness, darkness?
没有出路，让我告诉你当悲伤流过一个人的心
No way out, let me tell you When
the sadness flowing through one's heart
当悲伤流过一个人的心
When the sadness flowing
through one's heart
像刀一样切，
cuts like a knife,
像刀子一样切，
S在响吗？
cuts like a knife,
Singing?
像刀一样切，
Cuts like a knife,
它留下了一个开放的伤口
Mikumo！
it leaves an open wound
Mikumo!
它留下了一个开放的伤口
It leaves an open wound
他们在动摇吗？！
it leaves an open wound
They're wavering?!
它留下了一个开放的伤口
It leaves an open wound
它留下了一个开放的伤口。
it leaves an open wound
I see.
我们必须尽可能地破坏敌人的
Bio折叠波！
We have to disrupt the enemy's
Bio-Fold Waves as much as possible!
挣扎了多久？我们必须尽可能地破坏敌人的生物折叠波！
For how long have [ struggled? We have to disrupt
the enemy's Bio-Fold Waves as much as possible!
挣扎了多久？
For how long have [ struggled?
挣扎了多久？就在你身后！
Right behind you!
挣扎了多久？
For how long have [ struggled?
出口不见了
The exit is nowhere to be found
出口无处可寻
不用担心我们！去
The exit is nowhere to be found
Don't worry about us! Go!
别担心我们！去
没有时间害怕，不用担心我们！去
No time to be afraid,
Don't worry about us! Go!
没有时间害怕，
No time to be afraid,
没有时间害怕，很好。走吧！
Very well. Let's go!
没有时间害怕，
No time to be afraid,
没有时间害怕，-噢，先生！
-是的，先生！
No time to be afraid, - Oorah sir!
- Yes sir!
-噢，先生！
-是的，先生！
- Oorah sir!
- Yes sir!
因为时间不等人-噢，先生！
-是的，先生！
Because time waits for no one - Oorah sir!
- Yes sir!
因为时间不等人
Because time waits for no one
因为时间不等人。
because time waits for no one
Roger.
因为时间不等人
Because time waits for no one
Freyja。。。
because time waits for no one
Freyja...
因为时间不等人
because time waits for no one
因为时间不等人，所以我不会没事的。开始做
I'll be fine. Get going!
剥下你内心深处的痂，
Peel off that scab deep in your heart,
赤手空拳
with your own bare hands
迈向勇敢的新世界，下一步/
Onward to a brave new world, NEXT/
迈向一个勇敢的新世界，NEXT/
Delta Flight，跟我来！
Onward to a brave new world, NEXT/
Delta Flight, follow me!
迈向勇敢的新世界，下一步/
Onward to a brave new world, NEXT/
迈向一个勇敢的新世界，下一个/
Hmm？
Onward to a brave new world, NEXT/
Hmm?
迈向勇敢的新世界，下一步/
Onward to a brave new world, NEXT/
苦难仍在继续。所以……终于开始唱了
eh，Walkure？现在你会怎么回应，警报器？
Misery ongoing. So... Finally started singing
eh, Walkure? Now how will you respond, Siren?
所以……终于开始唱歌了，嗯，瓦库尔？
你怎么回应，警报器？
So... Finally started singing eh, Walkure?
Now how will you respond, Siren?
它仍然痛得要命所以……终于开始唱歌了，是吗，沃尔科尔？现在你会怎么回应，警报器？
It still hurts like hell So... Finally started
singing eh, Walkure? Now how will you respond, Siren?
所以……终于开始唱歌了，嗯，瓦库尔？
你怎么回应，警报器？
So... Finally started singing eh, Walkure?
Now how will you respond, Siren?
在狂风中咬着嘴唇（一直在那里，做了！）所以……最后开始唱歌了，嗯，Walkure？现在你会怎么回应，警报器？
Biting your lips against the blasting wind (been there, done that!) So...
Finally started singing eh, Walkure? Now how will you respond, Siren?
在狂风的吹拂下咬着嘴唇（去过那里，做过！）
Biting your lips against the blasting wind
(been there, done that!)
在狂风中咬着嘴唇（一直在那里，做了！）
They袭击了Freyja的村庄。我不会让他们这么干的！
Biting your lips against the blasting wind (been there, done that!)
They attacked Freyja's village. I won't let them gel away with this!
他们袭击了Freyja的村庄。
I不会让他们逍遥法外的！
They attacked Freyja's village.
I won't let them get away with this!
超过限制，去做吧。他们袭击了NFreyja的村庄。我不会让他们逍遥法外的！
Over the limit, go for it. Pulse thumping They attacked
Freyja's village. I won't let them get away with this!
超过限制，去做吧。脉冲重击
Over the limit, go for it. Pulse thumping
超过限制，去做吧。脉冲砰砰响
Calm down。首先使用MRV导弹。
Over the limit, go for it. Pulse thumping
Calm down. Use your MRV missiles first.
超越消失点
I已经知道！
Go beyond the vanishing point
I know already!
超越消失点
Go beyond the vanishing point
重开的伤口看起来像野兽
That reopened wound looks like a beast
说不，说不，你说什么
Say na na na na, what you say
我要把你变成我的，娜！/不！不！钠/
I'm gonna make you mine, Na!/ Na! Na! Na/
你疯了吗？永远不要让你走
Are you crazy? Never let you go
你疯了吗？永远不要让你走他们躲过了MRV/
They dodged the MRVs?/
你得到了，永远不知道，在牺牲中，他们可以移动！
You got it, never know, in sacrifice
Damn, they can move!
你得到了，永远不知道，牺牲
You got it, never know, in sacrifice
你得到了，永远不知道，在牺牲
Delta 56/在你的六个！
You got it, never know, in sacrifice
Delta 56/ On your six!
你得到了，永远不知道，牺牲
You got it, never know, in sacrifice
你做到了，永远不知道，牺牲是不可能的！
Impossible!
不可能的
（是的，我知道，我知道）
不可能！
(Yes I know, I know)
Impossible!
（是的，我知道，我知道）
(Yes I know, I know)
到底怎么回事？你说得对，这些未知的怪物发出了强大的
金色波浪！
What the hell is going on? You're right Strong
Fold Wave are emitting from these unknown bogeys!
太疯狂了，分解它，分解它
So crazy, break it down,
break it down, break it down
太疯狂了，把它分解，分解，分解他们是一种新型的幽灵！
So crazy, break it down, break it down,
break it down They're some new type of Ghost!
太疯狂了，分解它，分解它
So crazy, break it down,
break it down, break it down
太疯狂了，把它打碎，打碎，再打碎它
down G-Ghosts？！即使如此，他们的机动方式。。。
So crazy, break it down, break it down, break it
down G-Ghosts?! Even so, the way they maneuver...
你是认真的吗？也许，也许…哦
Are you serious? Maybe, maybe...Oh
你是认真的吗？也许，也许……噢，比格·伯伦茨的主要枪支占85%
Sigur Berrentzs main guns at 85%
Sigur Berrentz的主要枪支占85%
让它成为现实吧
Just make it a reality
Sigur Berrentzs main guns at 85%
让它成为现实
Just make it a reality
让它成为现实所有的战士
清除Sigur Berrentz的火力线！
Just make it a reality All fighters
clear the Sigur Berrentzs' line of fire!
所有战士清除
Sigur Berrentzs的火力线！
All fighters clear the
Sigur Berrentzs' line of fire!
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？所有
战士清除Sigur Berrentz的火力线！
So crazy, crazy, get out! What do you say? All
fighters clear the Sigur Berrentzs' line of fire!
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？
So crazy, crazy, get out! What do you say?
King Heinz！
King Heinz!
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？
So crazy, crazy, get out! What do you say?
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？\我向国王致敬！
All hail the King!
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？
So crazy, crazy, get out! What do you say?
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？能量
充电完毕！火线已全部清除！
So crazy, crazy, get out! What do you say? Energy
charge complete! Line of fire is all clear!
能量充电完成！
火线已全部清除！
Energy charge complete!
Line of fire is all clear!
! 知道你想要什么能量充电
完成！火线已全部清除！
! know what you want Energy charge
complete! Line of fire is all clear!
能量充电完成！
火线已全部清除！
Energy charge complete!
Line of fire is all clear!
你是唯一的一个，给我更高的能量
充电完成！火线已全部清除！
You're the only one, take me higher Energy
charge complete! Line of fire is all clear!
你是唯一的一个，让我更高
You're the only one, take me higher
你是唯一一个，带我更高一点！
Fire!
你是唯一的一个，让我更高
You're the only one, take me higher
告诉我，黑暗是什么意思？
Tell me, what's the meaning
of darkness, darkness?
告诉我，黑暗的含义是什么，黑暗？敌人旗舰主炮开火！
Tell me, what's the meaning of darkness,
darkness? Enemy flagship main guns firing!
没有出路，让我告诉你
No way out, let me tell you
Raise Dimensional Barrier。
Raise Dimensional Barrier.
没有出路，让我告诉你
No way out, let me tell you
哦哦给我带路，没有出路，没有出路
Oh! Oh! Show me the way,
oh no way, no way out
抓住他们了！
Got 'em!
倒霉！
Shit!
敌舰完好无损。
Enemy ship intact.
大概正在准备开火。
Presumably preparing
to fire their main cannon.
Sigur Berrentzs，封锁起来！
Sigur Berrentzs, barriers up!
但开火后我们没有足够的能量/
But we don't have enough
power after firing the main guns/
那就别无选择！
Then there's no choice!
De Enda公司
De Enda
乌拉诺德恩达
De Enda Ulano
乌拉诺国王陛下！
Your Majesty!
乌拉诺德恩达
De Enda Ulano
乌拉诺风之歌太紧张了。。。
The Wind Song is too much strain...
很高兴有一首押韵的klan delkez。。。
De glad a rhyme klan delkez...
很高兴有一首押韵的klan delkez……看在陛下的份上，不要让他们开枪！
De glad a rhyme klan delkez... For His Majesty's
sake, don't let them fire their main gun!
很高兴有一首押韵的klan delkez。。。
De glad a rhyme klan delkez...
很高兴有一首押韵的klan delkez…
Da/
De glad a rhyme klan delkez...
勒德拉姆
Le de raam lom
Delta Flight随时待命！
Delta Flight is here to assist!
勒德拉姆
Le de raam lom
Klano Klano de aura公司
Klano Klano de aura
Klano Klano de aura-拿着这个！
-拿着这个！
Klano Klano de aura - Take this!
- Take this!
Klano Klano de aura公司
Klano Klano de aura
-那些东西是分开的？！
——展开！
-Those things detached?!
-Spread out!
他们到处都是！
They're everywhere!
该死！
Dammit!
Xao！
Xao!
不能打他们！不好的。。。
Can't hit 'em! Not good...
De Enda公司
De Enda
乌拉诺德恩达
De Enda Ulano
乌兰诺市。
Now.
乌拉诺德恩达
De Enda Ulano
De gappy a押韵klan-
De glad a rhyme klan—
…好吧，我很高兴有一首押韵的klan-
...All right,
好吧
! 知道你不会回头看。
So不要回头看
! know you don't look back.
So don't look back
…lom（长）
...lom
Klano Klano de aura公司
Klano Klano de aura
德法利约兹兰
De fallo yoo zlam
Tres degna zula公司
Tres degna zula
So这是风之力量的歌手。。。
So this is the Singer of the Wind's power...
所以这就是风之歌的力量。。。
德尔克……这是风之力量的歌者。。。
Del k...
So this is the Singer of the Wind's power...
删除。。。
Del k...
删除……但现在结束。
But this ends now.
你是认真的吗？也许，也许/
Are you serious? Maybe, maybe... Of/
让它成为现实
Just make it a reality
疯了，快出去！你怎么说？
不要让他们通过！
So crazy crazy, get out! What do you say?
Don't let them through!
疯了，快出去！你怎么说？
So crazy crazy, get out! What do you say?
Roger（诺格）/
Roger/
疯了，快出去！你怎么说？
So crazy crazy, get out! What do you say?
! 知道你想要什么
! know what you want
你是唯一的一个，让我更高
You're the only one, take me higher
你是唯一的，带我更高一点！
Kassim!
告诉我，黑暗是什么意思？
Tell me, what's the meaning
of darkness, darkness?
告诉我，黑暗的含义是什么，黑暗？你不能通过！
Tell me, what's the meaning of darkness,
darkness? You're not getting though!
没有出路，让我告诉你
No way out, let me tell you
哦哦给我带路，没有路，没有出路什么？！
Oh! Oh! Show me the way,
oh no way, no way out What?!
哦哦给我带路，没有出路，没有出路
Oh! Oh! Show me the way,
oh no way, no way out
陛下！
Your Majesty!
他们不会的！
They wouldn't!
不可能。
No way.
他们在大气中使用反作用弹头？
They used Reaction warheads in-atmosphere?
这些人都疯了！
These people are crazy!
Sigur Berrentz家倒闭了。。。
The Sigur Berrentzs is down...
没事的。
It'll be okay.
约翰神父，里面没人安全。
Father Johann,
everyone's safely inside.
啊！约翰神父。。。
Ugh! Father Johann...
就是这样吗？！
Is that it?!
海亚特！
Hayate!
没有了！
No more!
我用沾满鲜血的声音鼓起勇气大声喊道
In a voice tainted with blood, I mustered
my strength and shouted out
抹去黑夜的黑暗/
Wipe away the darkness of the night/
抹去夜晚的黑暗/
Siren的生物折叠波发射
Wipe away the darkness of the night/
Siren's Bio-Fold Wave emission
警报器的生物折叠波发射
痛苦的眼泪是流线，
Siren的生物折叠波发射
Bitter tears are streamliners,
Siren's Bio-Fold Wave emission
痛苦的眼泪是流线型的，
Bitter tears are streamliners,
苦涩的眼泪是流线型的，已经下降到18%。
has dropped to 18%.
即将闪耀光芒
About to sparkle and shine
即将闪耀光芒，
about to sparkle and shine
In reaction to Walkure's song,
照亮我的道路，他们站在我这边，似乎已经进入了深度学习模式。
Lighting my way, they're on my side it
seems to have entered deep learning mode.
照亮我的路，他们在我身边
Lighting my way, they're on my side
照亮我的路，他们也站在我这边，我们已经控制了大部分目标区域。
Lighting my way, they're on my side Just as well,
we've seized control of most of the targeted area.
好好研究他们，了解他们的特点。
Study them well and learn their traits.
苦难仍在继续。\好好研究他们，了解他们的特点。
Misery ongoing.
Study them well and learn their traits.
苦难仍在继续。
Misery ongoing.
仍然痛得要命
It still hurts like hell
它仍然痛得要命-他们的动作停止了！
-现在！
It still hurts like hell - Their movement's off!
- Now!
我相信你，这是预先决定的
I believe in you, it's predetermined
(been there, done that!)
我相信你，这是预先决定的他们已经康复了！
I believe in you, it's predetermined
(been there, done that!) They've recovered!
我相信你，这是预先决定的
I believe in you, it's predetermined
(been there, done that!)
超出限制。冲刺\猛击。
Over the limit. dash for it
Pulse thumping.
超过极限，冲刺。脉搏跳动。\不能再这样下去了……有什么事吗？
Over the limit, dash for it. Pulse thumping.
Can't keep this up... Something's incoming?
超出限制。冲刺\猛击。
Over the limit. dash for it
Pulse thumping.
超越消失点
Go beyond the vanishing point
Reinforcements？！
Reinforcements?!
重开的伤口
Macross Gigasion
That reopened wound
The Macross Gigasion from
那重新打开的伤口
That reopened wound
那个重开的伤口Xaos Listania
Branch？它在这里做什么？
That reopened wound Xaos Listania
Branch? What's it doing here?
Xaos Listania分行？
它在这里做什么？
Xaos Listania Branch?
What's it doing here?
看起来像野兽Xaos Listania牧场？它在这里做什么？
looks like a beast Xaos Listania
Branch? What's it doing here?
看起来像只野兽
looks like a beast
这么大的船怎么样。。。
How's a ship that size...
那种飞行风格，是……吗。。。？
That flying style, is that...?
向所有战士致敬。
Gigasion to all fighters.
登上飞机，立即从温德米尔撤退。
Get aboard for immediate
withdrawal from Windermere.
但是
But...
Walkire已被提取。
移动它/
Walkire are already being extracted.
Move it/
收到。
Copy that.
我想你能跟上。博格？
Think you can keep up, It. Bogue?
真是无耻/
What gall!/
嘿，我很抱歉…我们要退出了！
Heh, my apologies... We're pulling out!
开始/着陆。那些严重受损的先去。
Commence /landing. Those
heavily damaged go first.
很抱歉
Sorry!
哦，不，你不要！
Oh no you don't!
不好的！
Not good!
我去叫Walkure！
I'll get Walkure!
谢谢
Thanks!
海亚特！
Hayate!
你没事吧？海亚特！海亚特！
You okay? Hayate! Hayate!
是 啊以某种方式
Yeah. Somehow...
海因兹·内里奇·温德米尔国王，我们特此通知您
King Heinz Nehrich Windermere,
we hereby inform you that
德温特现在在我们的控制之下。
Derwent is now under our control.
如果你想避免更多平民伤亡，
If you wish to avoid
further civilian casualties,
你会立刻投降的。
you will surrender at once.
这怎么样？你觉得其他地方痛吗？
How's this? Do you feel
pain anywhere else?
没有，但我感觉不到我的腿。。。
No, but I can't feel my legs...
袭击太突然了，我的人。。。
The attack was so sudden, my men...
不要放弃希望，他们可能就在另一个房间里。
Don't give up hope, they
might just be in another room.
给我拿治疗Windermerians的数据！
Get me the data on treating Windermerians!
还有多少人受伤？！
How many more wounded are there?!
拉格纳三角洲航班第三飞行翼报告，长官。
Delta Flight of Ragna 3rd
Fighter Wing reporting sir.
队长，我们感谢你的救援。
Captain, we thank you for the rescue.
你能向我们介绍一下目前的情况吗。。。
Can you brief us on the current situation...
他一定是这艘船的新西兰中央档案管理员。
He must be this ship's
Zentradi archivist.
隐马尔可夫模型？
Hmm?
埃克塞多尔·福尔莫参谋长。。。
Staff Officer Exedol Folmo...
已经有一段时间了，幻影。
It's been a while, Mirage.
如果你在这里，那意味着。。。
If you're here, that means...
我看你还没有找到你的工作。幻景
I see you're still leaving your
blind spot wide open, It. Mirage.
那是。。。
That's...
我是马克西米利安·杰尼乌斯，马十字队队长。
I'm Maximilian Jenius, captain
of the Ma cross Gigasion.
我想一定是你，爷爷。
I thought it must be you, grandfather.
祖父
Grandfather?
传奇天才飞行员。
The legendary genius ace pilot.
马英九第七次战役的舰长穿越了第七舰队。
And captain of Battle 7 of the Ma cross 7 Fleet.
哇！
Whoa!
我听说你从军队退役了，爷爷。你在这里干什么？
I heard you retired from the military,
Grandfather. What are you doing here?
我被Xaos招募。
I was recruited by Xaos.
救援命令来自M女士。
Rescue orders came from Lady M.
与总部的沟通还没有结束吗？
Aren't communications with HQ still out?
命令被直接传送到我的大脑。
The order was transmitted
directly to my brain.
M女士的联络官
Lady M's Fold comms officer
我有相同的DNA，所以。。。
and I are of the same DNA, so...
拉格纳也落入了敌人手中。
Ragna has also fallen to the enemy.
上尉，医务室报告说
Captain, med bay is reporting that
被带走的风车手情况危急。。。
the Windermerian taken
aboard is in critical condition...
约翰神父！
Father Johann!
显然，他想用它说话。海亚特·伊梅尔曼。
Apparently he wishes to speak
with It. Hayate Immelmann.
我
Me?
你是赖特的。。。
You are Wright's...
赖特·伊梅尔曼的儿子，是吗？
Wright Immelmann's boy, yes?
你的风与他的风相连，我能感觉到。
Your wind is connected
to his, I can feel it.
充满对自由和世界的爱的风。
A wind full of love for freedom
and for the world.
你怎么知道我爸爸的？
How do you know about my dad?
你的吊坠。是我把它寄给你妈妈的。
Your pendant. I was the one
who sent it to your mother.
你但为什么？
You? But why?
嗯，你父亲驻扎在温德米尔。
Well, your father was
stationed on Windermere.
呵呵。。。？
Huh...?
赖特·伊梅尔曼少校是一名特工，
Major Wright Immelmann
was a special operative,
他的任务是调查寺庙和专业文化遗址。
his mission was to investigate
temples and Pro to culture ruins.
特工？我爸爸？
A special operative? My dad?
不要担心。
Worry not.
他从未做过任何伤害我们人民的事。
He never did anything to harm our people.
在执行任务期间，有人从温德米尔庙宇里拿走了一些东西。
During his mission, something was
taken from a Windermerian temple.
这是Pro to文化的遗迹。。。
It was a relic of the Pro to culture...
明星歌手的细胞样本。
Cell samples of
the Singers of the Stars.
那一定是Mikumo的。。。
That must be Mikumo's...
带走他们的罪犯是联合国政府外交官。
The culprit who took them
was a U.N. Government diplomat.
他也是一名特工。
He was really an operative as well.
Wright要求我帮助检索样本。。。
Wright asked me to help
retrieve the samples...
我们只能找到其中一个。
We were able to recover only one of them.
随后，温德米尔与联合国政府的关系恶化，
Then relations between Windermere
and the U.N. Government soured,
无法退回样品。
making it impossible to return the sample.
进入女士M。。。
Enter Lady M...
我从未想过赖特少校会与《星光之星》合作。
I never imagined Major Wright was
involved with the Singer of the Stars.
他去寻找另一个样本，这花了他的生命。。。
He went after the other sample,
and it cost him his life...
你父亲为
Windermere奋斗到最后-
Windermere to the very end—
Your father fought for
约翰神父！
Father Johann!
没有必要悲伤，
There is no need to be sad,
我只是在履行我的职责。
I am only fulfilling my duty.
赖特曾经说过，所有的风都是一体的。
Wright used to say that
all winds will be as one.
我们未能阻止战争，
We failed to prevent the war,
但总有一天。。。
but someday...
弗雷亚。
Freyja.
我，我在这里！
I-I'm here!
太亮的符文会缩短人的寿命。
A rune that shines too bright
can shorten one's life.
你必须仔细考虑这口井。
You must reflect on this well.
你为什么活着？
你唱什么。。。
For what do you live?
For what do you sing...
约翰神父。。。
Father Johann...
随风而行，
到风之泉。。。
Go with the Wind,
to the Fountain of Wind...
海亚特？
Hayate?
风车人与风融为一体
A Windermerian becoming one with the wind
就是我们的时间结束的时候。\你以前从未见过。。。
is when our time ends.
So you've never seen it before...
偷样品的探员
The agent who stole the samples
目前在Epsilon工作。
ls currently working for Epsilon.
Epsilon基金会，一家拥有数千家公司的企业集团。
The Epsilon Foundation, a conglomerate
with thousands of companies to its name.
我听过很多关于他们的谣言。
I've heard plenty of
shady rumors about them.
西德尼·亨特。
Sidney Hunt.
他似乎用样品在Epsilon为自己买了一个好职位。
It seems he bought himself a fine
position at Epsilon with the sample.
他是我爸爸后面的人。。。
He's the guy behind my dad's...
这个人偷走了“另一位明星歌手”。。。
This man who stole the
other Singer of the Stars'...
我们听到的声音听起来像Mikumo的，但是。。。
That voice we heard
sounded like Mikumo's, but...
里面没有灵魂。
There was no soul in it.
它本身是一片空旷而漆黑的黑暗。
It was empty and pitch
black like darkness itself.
一个Yamikumo。
A Yamikumo.
也许它还没有完全成形。
Maybe it's not fully-formed.
他们可能只制造了脑细胞和其他必要的器官。
They might have only made brain
cells and other necessary organs.
但我们感觉到的那个歌手呢？
But what about that singer we sensed?
一个虚拟人。。。
A virturoid...
Bio Fold Waves具有传递音乐和情感的能力
Bio-Fold Waves have the power
to convey music and emotions
通过与折叠石英共振来穿越空间和时间。
through space and time by
resonating with Fold Quartz.
他们很可能正在使用
It's very possible that they're using
明星力量的歌唱者
the Singer of the Stars' power
to boost the energy of their
反应引擎和折叠武器。
Reaction Engines and Fold weapons.
你是说他们把音乐当作武器？
You mean they're using music as a weapon?
来自Windermere的视频消息正在Galaxy Network上广播。
A video message from Windermere
ls being broadcast on the Galaxy Network.
来自温德米尔？
From Windermere?
-把它放在显示器上。
-是的，先生。
- Put it up on the monitor.
- Aye sir.
这是什么？
What's this?
自古以来，人类就发动战争
Since ancient times, humanity has made war
在整个历史过程中，造成了许多死亡和破坏。
throughout history, causing much
death and destruction along the way.
我们是海姆达尔，
We are Heimdall,
我们来到这里是为了将人类从生锈的锁链中解放出来。
and we are here to liberate
humanity from its rusted chains.
解放
Liberate?
我们的目标是消灭银河系中的联合国政府、联合国、预防母婴传播中心、，
Our objective is to rid the galaxy of
the U.N. Government, N.U.N.S., PMCs,
还有一个暗中操纵他们的人，M女士。
and the one secretly pulling
all their strings, Lady M.
M女士是一个幕后操纵联合国政府的影子人物
Lady M is a shadowy figure that has been
manipulating the U.N. Government behind
禁止使用先进技术并秘密统治人类的场景。
the scenes, banning the use of advanced
technology and ruling humanity in secret.
Sharon Apple？！
Sharon Apple?!
不可能！
No way!
禁止人工授精和克隆研究，限制专业培养技术，
The ban on A.I. and cloning research, the
restrictions on Pro to culture technology,
所有这些都是为了加强他们对先进技术的垄断。
all implemented to enforce their
monopoly over advanced technology.
如果向公众公开，许多悲剧本可以避免，
Many tragedies could've been averted if
these had been available to the public,
温德米尔起义就是其中之一。
the Windermerian revolt being one of them.
/是M女士用专业人士留下的细胞样本进行培养
/It was Lady M who used cell samples
left behind by the Pro to culture
创建超维度声武器Mikumo Guynemer，
to create the Super Dimensional
Sound Weapon Mikumo Guynemer,
利用本应被禁止的克隆技术。
utilizing cloning technology that
was supposed to be banned.
这个人。。。
This man...
我们再也不能容忍这种压制了。
We cannot tolerate this
oppression any longer.
我们将推翻这些暴君，将银河系带入一个新时代/！
We shall overthrow these tyrants
and usher the galaxy into a new age/!
视频分析完成。
Video analysis complete.
伊恩·克伦威尔，
Ian Cromwell,
马英九前船长在联合国第七舰队穿越纳斯特拉。
former captain of the Ma cross
Astrea in N.U.N.S.' Seventh Fleet.
八年前，他随船前往MIA。
He went MIA along with
his ship eight years ago.
所以，“铁”克伦威尔还活着。
So, "Iron" Cromwell is still alive.
他是扎尔格甘茨战役的英雄，
He was the hero of the
Battle of Zalg-gantz,
他征服的地方
where he subdued
只有一艘船的整个无赖Zentradi
fleet。
an entire rogue Zentradi
fleet with just one ship.
为什么英雄会这样做？
Why would a hero do this?
看起来像是
That looks like
非法的
Sharon Apple型量子人工智能系统的高级模型。
an advanced model of the illegal
Sharon Apple type quantum A.I. system.
但是，他们肯定没有使用生物神经芯片
But instead of a bio-neural
chip, they must've
用星之歌手的牢房。
used the Singer of the Stars' cells.
所以他们带走了
Windermere和Ragna，
So that's why they took
Windermere and Ragna,
他们想用专业文化作为扩音器。。。
they want to use the Pro to culture
ruins as amplifiers...
如果他们占领了小叶星团的所有废墟，银河系将。。。
If they seize all the ruins in the
Globular Cluster, the galaxy would...
根据M女士的命令，
By the order of Lady M,
我们要阻止敌人的计划，收复星际之歌的细胞。
we are to stop the enemy's plan and
recover the Singer of the Stars' cells.
我根本无法应付敌人的敏捷。
I wasn't able to handle
the enemy's agility at all.
它们会飞吗？
Will they fly?
别担心，我们会把它们修补好的
Don't worry, we'll patch them up real nice
带有备用Kairos零件。
with spare Kairos parts.
我分析了敌人的
I analyzed the enemy's
Bio Fold Wave System在技术团队的帮助下，
Bio-Fold Wave System with
the help of the tech team here,
因此，我们正在添加更多折叠石英，并更新放大器
so we're adding more Fold Quartz
and updating the amplifiers
在你的每一个女武神身上。
on each of your Valkyries.
如果他们能做到，我们没有理由不能。
If they can do it, there's
no reason we can't.
折叠石英应能对我们的音乐做出反应，并提高Valkyries的性能。
The Fold Quartz should react to our music
and boost the Valkyries' performance.
就好像我们把音乐当作武器一样。。。
As if we're using our music as a weapon...
这不是真的。
That's not true.
他说得对。你的音乐给了我们力量。
He's right. Your music gives us strength.
保护他人的力量。
The strength to protect others.
保护……的音乐。。。
Music that protects...
甜美的米拉米拉！你真可爱！
Sweet Mira-Mira! You're such a cutie!
他们在对我施压！
T-They're pressing against me!
不太近！
Not so close!
-请不要这么近！\你也很可爱，哈亚·哈亚。
- Not so close please!
- You're very sweet too, Haya-Haya.
是的，是的，好的。
Yeah yeah, okay.
我想知道Freyja是否没事。。。
I wonder if Freyja's okay...
说实话，看到约翰神父去世，我有点震惊。
To tell the truth, I was a little shocked
seeing Father Johann die.
这确实让我们明白了一个事实：我们是非常不同的种族。
It really drove home the fact
that we're very different races.
结晶…现在我想到了，
Crystallization... Now that I think of it,
Freyja也有迹象。。。
Freyja also showed signs...
这一定是Pro to culture系统的副作用。
That must've just been a side-effect
of the Pro to culture system.
当系统停止时，它停止了。。。
It stopped when the system did...
是的，我可能想得太多了。
Yes, I'm probably over thinking things.
现在，即使你也必须意识到这一点。
Now even you must realize it.
我们与地球人不同。
We're different than the Earthlings.
那是。。。
That's...
我们的位置就在那风里。
Our place is within that Wind.
我会取回温德米尔，不管花多少钱。
I will take back Windermere,
no matter the cost.
/克伦威尔似乎在很多情况下，
/It seems that Cromwell
has, on many occasions,
请求政府解除对禁用技术的禁令。
petitioned the government to
lift the ban on forbidden technology.
他的论点是，使用无人驾驶飞机可以减少人员伤亡，
His argument was that the use of unmanned
drones could reduce human casualties,
而控制论和克隆技术可以使在战斗中受伤的士兵受益。
while cybernetic and cloning technology
could benefit soldiers injured in battle.
然后，在瓦格宁战役中，他建议使用MDE弹头
Then, during the Battle of Wagenin, he
recommended using MDE warheads
阻止强大敌人的入侵。
He被忽略了。
to halt an invasion by a powerful enemy.
He was ignored.
结果，他的舰队和他的母星都被摧毁了。
As a result, his fleet and his
home planet were wiped out.
像他这样的人，幸存了下来。。。
A man like him, having survived
something like that...
他已经没有什么可失去的了。
He's got nothing left to lose.
没有什么比受伤的野兽更危险的了。
There's nothing so dangerous
as a wounded beast.
这个Heimdall小组怎么样？
What about this Heimdall group?
我以前听说过。人们对秘密行动的M女士感到不快。
I've heard of it before. People displeased
with Lady M, who operate in secret.
N、 美国还没有决定该怎么办。
N.U.N.S. still hasn't decided
what to do about them yet.
接近目的地。
Approaching destination.
我们的临时行动基地。
Our makeshift base of operations.
我懂了。一颗退役的
Zentradi工厂卫星。。。
I see. A decommissioned
Zentradi factory satellite...
N、 美国救援船？
N.U.N.S. rescue craft?
那些新的敌机舰队的幸存者。
Survivors from a fleet that ran
into those new enemy fighters.
它Bogue Con Vaart在这里。我正在帮你一个忙，加入达美航空。
It. Bogue Con-Vaart here. I'm doing
you a favor and joining Delta Flight.
我会告诉你，我不经常做这种服务。
I'll have you know that I don't
do this kind of service often.
这是真的，先生？
This for real sir?
这是真的。
It's for real.
现在，让我们开始吧。
Now, let's get started.
1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8.
别开玩笑了
Quit joking around
-停下来
-说真的
-Stop it
-Seriously
-没有了
-迷失方向
-No more
-Get lost
别把我当傻瓜看待
Don't treat me like I'm stupid
哇！
Wow
你是个说话的人
You're one to talk
那个混蛋，你这个混蛋
That son of a bitch, you son of a bitch
你已经走了
Just go away already
你这个偷梦的流氓
You dream-stealing rogue
哇！
Wow
嘿，小姐，那些家伙是披着羊皮的狼
Hey Miss, those guys are
wolves in sheep's clothing
他们躺在那里等着，视线被锁定。然后他们向你扑来
They're lying in wait, their sights
locked on. Then they swoop in on you
这些受骗的傻瓜毫无羞耻感
These deluded fools have no shame
这些受骗的傻瓜毫无羞耻感，敌人战斗数据上传到了超级幽灵无人机。
These deluded fools have no shame Enemy
combat data uploaded to Super Ghost drones.
这些受骗的傻瓜毫无羞耻感
These deluded fools have no shame
这些受骗的傻瓜毫无羞耻感，将限制器减少了60%。
Reducing limiter by 60%.
这些受骗的傻瓜毫无羞耻感
These deluded fools have no shame
他们甚至不了解心痛
They don't even understand heartache
他们甚至不理解心痛的心情。。。！
Slippery sun of a...!
滑溜的太阳。。。！
你喜欢什么类型的女孩？（你这个傻瓜）一个……的轻浮的太阳。。。！
Your type of girl? (you fool)
Slippery sun of a...!
你喜欢什么类型的女孩？（你这个傻瓜）
Your type of girl? (you fool)
你喜欢什么类型的女孩？（你这个傻瓜）该死，什么都打不中！
Dammit, can't hit a thing!
妈的，什么都打不中！
别逗我笑了
Dammit，什么都打不中！
Don't make me laugh
Dammit, can't hit a thing!
别让我笑
Don't make me laugh
别逗我笑他们很快！
They're fast!
他们很快！
看见（看到了吗？）
See? (See?)
They're fast!
看见（看到了吗？）
See? (See?)
一个不好的灌洗袋，
A no good douche bag,
就像他们说的那样
Just like they say
就像他们说的那样，女孩们，加油！
Alright girls, hit it!
就像他们说的那样
Just like they say
所以
So...
来吧，女人们，提高嗓门，大声点
Come on women, raise your voices,
make some noise
这个世界上只有一个真理
There's only one truth in this world
看看吧
Take a look
少女的纯洁如此迷人，
A maiden's purity is so bewitching,
它会让你兴奋不已，让你目瞪口呆
it'll thrill you and leave you staggering
这会让你兴奋不已，让你惊愕不已
谢谢，幻影！
it'll thrill you and leave you staggering
Thanks, Mirage!
它会让你兴奋不已，让你目瞪口呆
It'll thrill you and leave you staggering
它会让你兴奋不已，让你惊愕不已。不用谢我，我们走吧/
it'll thrill you and leave you staggering
Don't thank me, let's go/
永远不会
It'll never ever
代表这个
stand for this
! 不会让任何人说一切都毁了
! won't let anyone say
that everything's ruined
! 如果一切都乱七八糟，也不在乎
! don't care if everything gets messed up
别开玩笑了
Quit joking around
-停下来
-说真的
-Stop it
-Seriously
-没有了
-迷失方向
-No more
-Get lost
别把我当傻瓜看待
Stop treating me like I'm stupid
哇，我们做到了。。。
Wow
We did it...
哇！
Wow
哇，不是真的。这些与真实的东西不相比较。
Wow Not really. These don't
compare to the real thing.
不是真的。这些与真实的东西不相比较。
Not really. These don't
compare to the real thing.
精确地
Precisely!
AYE-297为什么这里有蓝色Durandal？
AYE-297 Why's there a
blue Durandal out here?
不可能！
It can't be!
我来了！
Here I come!
一个单人间
A single
一个
Whoa！
A single
Whoa!
哇！
（单曲）
Whoa！
(single)
Whoa!
（单个）
(single)
声音很小
Voice is small
这很糟糕，我们必须齐声歌唱！
voice is small
This is bad, we have to sing as one!
这太糟糕了，我们必须齐声歌唱！
所以它可以被掐灭。这太糟糕了，我们必须齐声歌唱！
So it can be snuffed out
This is bad, we have to sing as one!
所以它可以被掐灭
So it can be snuffed out
Copy！
so it can be snuffed out
Copy!
所以它可以被掐灭
So it can be snuffed out
这样它就可以被掐灭了
Gah！多大的风啊！但是
so it can be snuffed out
Gah! What a wind! But...!
所以它可以被掐灭
So it can be snuffed out
但如果我们超越时间汇聚在一起
（跨海）
But if we converge beyond time
(across the sea)
整个（全部）
Crimson Knight！
The entire (entire)
Crimson Knight!
整个（整体）
The entire (entire)
将来
Future
未来
Outta我的路！
future
Outta my way!
将来
Future
未来你离开我的！
future
You get outta mine!
你离开我的！
是我们的，你离开我的！
Is ours
You get outta mine!
是我们的吗
Is ours
是我们的
Delta 56和6，你在做什么？！
is ours
Delta 56 and 6, what are you doing?!
是我们的吗
Is ours
所以
So...
所以……NI跟不上他们。。。
I can't keep up with them...
我跟不上他们。。。
来吧，女人们，提高嗓门，制造一些我跟不上的噪音。。。
Come on women, raise your voices, make
some noise I can't keep up with them...
来吧，女人们，提高嗓门，大声点
Come on women, raise your voices,
make some noise
这个世界上只有一个真理
There's only one truth in this world
看看吧
Take a look
看看
Ah！
Take a look
Ah!
看看吧
Take a look
少女的纯洁如此迷人，
A maiden's purity is so bewitching,
少女的纯洁如此迷人，这到底是什么？
What the hell is this?
这到底是什么？
它会让你兴奋不已，让你惊愕不已。这到底是什么？
It'll thrill you and leave you staggering
What the hell is this?
它会让你兴奋不已，让你目瞪口呆
It'll thrill you and leave you staggering
它会让你兴奋不已，让你惊愕不已。他不像梅瑟或白骑士。
it'll thrill you and leave you staggering
He's not like Messer or the White Knight.
它会让你兴奋不已，让你目瞪口呆
It'll thrill you and leave you staggering
这会让你兴奋不已，让你目瞪口呆。我根本看不懂他！
it'll thrill you and leave you staggering
I can't read him at all!
我根本看不懂他！
我永远都不会读他的！
It'll never ever
I can't read him at all!
永远不会
It'll never ever
代表这个
stand for this
这就是臭名昭著的伊梅尔曼舞。
Ah, the notorious Immelmann Dance.
啊，臭名昭著的伊梅尔曼舞。
! 不会让任何人说一切都毁了啊，臭名昭著的伊梅尔曼舞。
! won't let anyone say that everything's
ruined Ah, the notorious Immelmann Dance.
! 不会让任何人说一切都毁了
! won't let anyone say
that everything's ruined
! 不会让任何人说一切都毁了他很有天赋，但是。。。！
! won't let anyone say that everything's
ruined He's got talent, but...!
! 如果一切都乱七八糟，也不在乎
! don't care if everything gets messed up
别开玩笑了
Quit joking around
-停下来
-说真的
-Stop it
-Seriously
-没有了
-迷失方向
-No more
-Get lost
别把我当傻瓜看待
Don't treat me like I'm stupid
哇！
Wow
你是个说话的人
You're one to talk
那个混蛋，你这个混蛋
That son of a bitch, you son of a bitch
你已经走了
Just go away already
你这个偷梦的流氓
You dream-stealing rogue
哇！
Wow
我想我会称之为“不可思议的舞蹈”。
Think I'll call that
the Incredible Dance.
伙计，我们被打败了。
Man, we got beat.
你飞得像只讨厌的昆虫。
You fly like a pesky insect.
那是什么？
What's that?
我的使命是解放温德米尔，
I'm on a mission to liberate Windermere,
所以别再妨碍我了！
so don't get in my way again!
我也是！
So am I!
为了你的女孩？
这不是一场游戏。
For your girl?
This isn't a game.
你说什么？
What did you say?
哇哦。拜托，伙计，别这样。
Whoa. C'mon man, don't.
Chuck的家人在Ragna。。。
Chuck's family's on Ragna...
Freyja的村庄在温德米尔！
and Freyja's village is on Windermere!
你在乎什么？你来自地球。
What do you care? You're from Earth.
他们现在是我生活的重要组成部分！
They're an important part of my life now!
所以我要夺回
Ragna和Windermere！
So I'm going to take back
Ragna and Windermere!
你们都在说话！
You're all talk!
让他们回来后你打算做什么？！你们这些该死的入侵者！
What do you plan on doing after you
get them back?! You damn invaders!
立刻停止！
Stop this at once!
它博格。
It. Bogue.
与Sv-262不同，VF-31的滚转速度会随您的移动而增加。
Unlike the Sv-262, the roll rate
of the VF-31 increases as you go.
尽快练习并习惯。
Practice and get used to that ASAP.
我知道。
I know.
海亚特·伊梅尔曼。
Hayate Immelmann.
我知道你的感受，但你需要有耐心。
I know how you're feeling,
but you need to have patience.
你们两个。我希望你在战场上表现出那样的精神。
You two. I wish you had shown
that much spirit on the battlefield.
祖父
Grandfather!
爷爷……队长，你没事吧？
Grandpa... Captain are you alright?
你太善良了，不可能成为一名优秀的拳击手。
You're too kind-hearted
to be a good fighter.
你缺乏杀戮的决心
You lack the resolve to go for the Kill
完全不顾他人。
with total disregard for others.
据我所知，你可能已经摆脱了一场浪漫的竞争。
You've probably even disengaged
from a romantic rivalry, for all I know.
T-那是。。。！
T-That's...!
本人——。
I--.
我没有你的天赋，队长。
I don't have your genius, captain.
是的，您确实缺乏成为高手的天赋。
Yes, you do lack the
talent to be an ace.
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
海亚特？
Hayate?
在这里
Here.
那是……奶奶的苹果！
That's... Grandma's apple!
对不起，我花了这么长时间才把它给你。
Sorry it took me so long to get it to you.
谢谢你，海亚特，谢谢你！
Thank you Hayate, thank you!
它被撞伤了，但里面有种子。
It's pretty bruised up, but
there are seeds inside.
我保证我会取回温德米尔，
I promise I'll take back Windermere,
然后我们用这些种子一起重新种植果园，好吗？
then we'll replant the orchard
with these seeds together, okay?
即使我们需要几年……不，几十年。
Even if it takes us years...
No, decades.
好吧，Freyja？
Okay, Freyja?
是的…当然。
Y-Yes... Sure.
非常感谢。
Thank you.
弗雷亚？
Freyja?
啊，我得走了。
Ah, I have to go.
嗯？嘿，Freyja？
Huh? Hey, Freyja?
你必须原谅海亚特。
You must forgive Hayate.
他是个白痴，但他是好意的。
He's an idiot, but he means well.
是的，我知道。
Yeah, I know.
但这就是你爱上的那种人，对吗？
But that's the kind of guy
you fell in love with, right?
是的，但是……我现在看到我不同了，
Yes but... I see now that I'm different,
而不是你和海亚特。
than you and Hayate.
所以你认为如果海亚特和你在一起，他会不高兴吗？
So you think Hayate won't
be happy if he's with you?
你不能自己决定事情！
You can't just decide things on your own!
你们两个必须一起想清楚！
Both of you have to
think this through together!
好吧。
Alrighty.
我也爱上了海亚特。
I was in love with Hayate too.
嗯？
Huh?
但我觉得我对他的感觉和你有点不同。
But I think my feelings for him were
a little bit different than yours.
我想我很钦佩他。
I guess I admired him.
我想成为一个像他一样自由的人。
I wanted to be a free spirit like him.
我支持你们俩。
I'm rooting for you both.
幻景
Mirage...
如今，星际婚姻已不再罕见。
And inter-planetary marriages are
no longer a rare thing these days.
哦，对了，马基纳告诉我。
Oh right, Makina told me.
麦克斯队长是第一个这样做的人！
Captain Max was the first one to do it!
M-我的祖父母不是一个好榜样！
M-My grandparents are not
a good example!
被小报评为最有可能分手的名人夫妇
Voted No.1 famous couple
most likely to split by the tabloids
连续50年。
for 50 years in a row.
公平地说，文章说
To be fair, the articles said
他们的问题更多的是他们的个性。
their problem was more their
personalities than anything else.
谈恋爱？我们也想加入混音！
Talking romance? We
wanna be in the mix too!
混合和搅拌。小心，不要混合。
Mixing and churning. Caution, do not mix.
来吧，不要再这样了！
Come on, not again!
我想我明白了
I thought I understood
我们的种族有多不同，但是。。。
how different our races were, but...
但这并没有改变你对她的看法，对吗？
But that doesn't change how
you feel about her right?
没有，但是…我想，
No but... I got to thinking,
她真的愿意和我在一起吗？
would she really be
happy being with me?
你们两个需要好好谈谈。
You two need to talk this through.
如果等到太迟了，你会后悔的。
If you wait until it's
too late, you'll regret it.
卡奈姆。。。
Kaname...
如果你半途而废，
If you half-ass this thing,
您将有所有Walkire要处理。知道了？
you'll have all of Walkire
to deal with. Got it?
是的，女士。
Yes ma'am.
你知道，我从来都不想当船长。
I never wanted to be
ship's captain you know.
当时，联合国海军缺少军官，
At the time, N.U.N.S.
was short on officers,
所以我别无选择，只能接受。
so I had no choice but to accept.
但即使到了现在，我仍然觉得自己生来就是一名飞行员，而不是别的什么。
But even now, I still feel I was
born to be a pilot and nothing else.
不过，恐怕幻影也不能这么说。
I'm afraid the same can't
be said for Mirage though.
是的，她并不是真正优秀的飞行员材料。
Yes, she's not really ace pilot material.
熄火气体？
Knockout gas?
你在那里干什么！
What are you doing there!
使沮丧
Get down!
阿拉德！
Arad!
阿拉德指挥官，你没事吧？
Commander Arad, are you alright?
我们的位置被泄露了。。。
Our location's been compromised...
恐怕比那更糟。
I'm afraid it's worse than that.
我道歉。我离开车站时。。。
My apologies. I was away
from my station when...
不，没关系。
No, it's alright.
我将把团队交给你负责，幻影。
I'm leaving the team in
your charge, Mirage.
罗杰。
Roger.
乐谱？
A musical score?
这是M女士的指示。
It's a directive from Lady M.
仅为Xaos的眼睛编码？
Encoded for Xaos' eyes only?
那东西窃取了信息，所以。。。
That thing hacked the message, so...
通过分析加密数据，
By analyzing the encrypted data,
我们的敌人一定知道他们能找到M女士的位置。
our enemy must've figured that they
can pinpoint Lady M's location.
麦克斯队长，
Captain Max,
我想你知道M女士的真实身份吧？
I assume you know Lady M's true identity?
他们的官方代号是
Lady Megaroad-01。
Their official codename is
Lady Megaroad-01.
Megaroad-01…你是说。。。？
Megaroad-01... You mean...?
2012年离开地球的第一批移民的旗舰。
The flagship of the First Emigration
Fleet that left Earth in 2012.
通信在2016年丢失，从那以后就一直丢失。。。
Comms were lost in 2016, and
they've been missing ever since...
然后是我们的一个附属组织
Then one of our affiliate organizations
拾取了来自子空间的折叠波传输
picked up a Fold Wave transmission
coming from subspace
使用与Megaroad-01相同的频率。
using the same frequency
as the Megaroad-01.
分析变速器后，
After analyzing the transmission,
我们发现它包含了
we found that it contained the
protocol codes needed to
解开星际之歌和职业文化遗址的神秘面纱。
unlock the mystery of the Star Song
and the Pro to culture ruins.
那么女士M是不是有人登上了Megaroad-01？
Then Lady M ls someone
aboard the Megaroad-01?
我们不知道。
We don't know.
我们甚至不确定能否将它们称为智能生命形式。
We're unsure if we can even
call them an intelligent life form.
你相信这样的事吗？
And you trusted such a thing?
至少他们不是我们的敌人。
They're not our enemy, at least.
目前为止。
For now.
你不知道。
You don't know that.
如果你问我，这位女士M和克伦威尔没什么不同。
If you ask me, this Lady M's
not so different from Cromwell.
这个星系的类人物种
The humanoid species of this galaxy
他们还太年轻，无法处理Pro to文化的遗迹。
are still too adolescent to handle
the relics of the Pro to culture.
/似乎M女士看着诺维尔文明，等待它成熟。
/It would seem that Lady M watches
over civilization, waiting for it to mature.
因此，我们不会犯50万年前NPro文化犯下的错误。
So we do not make the same mistakes the
Pro to culture made 500,000 years ago.
我们通知他们了吗？
Have we alerted them?
是的，但Megaroad-01在褶皱断层之间飘浮
Yes, but the Megaroad-01 is
caught adrift between Fold Faults
系统瘫痪。
with its systems crippled.
逃跑是不可能的。
Escape ls impossible.
不
No...
你是认真的吗？也许，也许/
Are you serious? Maybe, maybe... Of/
让它成为现实
Just make it a reality
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？
So crazy, crazy, get out! What do you say?
Fly！用爱的（爱的）
Fly! With love's (love's)
太疯狂了，疯了，出去！你怎么说？
So crazy, crazy, get out! What do you say?
Kiss（亲吻）
Kiss (kiss)
亲吻（Kiss）
! 知道你想要什么
Kiss（亲吻）
! know what you want
Kiss (kiss)
! 知道你想要什么
! know what you want
我知道你想要什么
Let的链接到时间的末尾
I know what you want
Let's link to the end of time
让我们链接到时间的末尾
你是唯一的一个，带我更高一点
You're the only one, take me higher
Let's link of the end of time
你是唯一的一个，让我更高
You're the only one, take me higher
你是唯一的，让我更高一点我爱你
I love you
你是唯一的一个，让我更高
You're the only one, take me higher
你是唯一一个，带我更高一点，打破激情的极限。。。
Breaking the limits of passion...
打破激情的极限。。。
绝对零度
Absolute zero with you
与你的绝对零
NEnemy Bio Fold Wave Song中立。
Absolute zero with you
Enemy Bio-Fold Wave Song neutralized.
（Hahn）高级折叠声音放大器正在工作！
(Hahn) Advanced Fold Sound
Amplifiers are working!
三角洲4号，七点钟有一队主力部队来了！
Delta 4, you've got a squadron of
Ghosts coming in at seven o'clock!
复制
Copy!
三角洲5号，集中注意力，不要靠近强盗。
Delta 5, keep your focus solely
on the approaching bandits.
明白了/
Got it/
三角洲3号，掩护三角洲5号的6号！
Delta 3, cover Delta 5's six!
我会点燃你的梦想
Delta 3，覆盖Delta 5的6！
I'll kindle your dreams
Delta 3, cover Delta 5's six!
拥抱你所相信的一切
Oorah先生！
Embrace all that you believe
Oorah sir!
拥抱你所相信的一切
Embrace all that you believe
Delta 6，强盗三点钟高！
Delta 6, bandits three o'clock high!
拥抱你所相信的一切
Embrace all that you believe
拥抱你相信的一切
Da/
Embrace all that you believe
鲁莽的基因
Reckless genes
几乎是谎言，心燃烧到爱的地步
Almost a lie, heart enflamed to the point of loving
甩掉它
Shake it off
到另一个维度，挤压我
to another dimension, squeeze me
狠狠地打，
Beating hard,
核心即将崩溃（看着我）
Cores about to crash (watch me)
爱自然的你
Loving the natural you
-眼泪——无法流泪
-Tears
-that can't be shed
-单独
-connect
-alone
-我们的命运
-our destinies
飞生活（迷恋）
Fly! Live (infatuatedly)
以（爱的）速度
At the speed (of love)
超级新星
Super Novatic
失去了翅膀，超级新星
Having lost my wings,
Super Novatic
失去了翅膀，
Having lost my wings,
我摔倒了
I fall
我有空
I'm free
我自由了他们加速了？！
They accelerated?!
他们加速了？！
最后他们加速了？！
At last
They accelerated?!
最后
At last
这首歌到底是什么？
at last
What the hell is this song?
最后
At last
最后，这股邪恶的风。。。
at last
This evil wind...
最后
at last
Bio折叠波！
Bio-Fold Waves!
生物折叠波！
它在倍增吗？！
Is it multiplying?!
现在我传递它是乘法吗？！
Now I pass
Is it multiplying?!
现在我通过了
Now I pass
现在我通过了分析…我们的歌唱。。。
Analyzed... our singing...
分析…我们的歌唱。。。
判断，分析…我们的歌唱。。。
Judgement,
Analyzed... our singing...
判断
Judgement,
判断，从我们身上学到了什么？
It learned from us?
判断
Judgement,
自以为是的人
on a self-righteous
以自以为是的态度，这是。。。！
Wait, this is...!
一个自以为是的人
On a self-righteous
上帝
god
上帝音乐是Euphoria。
Music is Euphoria.
上帝
God
上帝音乐是绝望。
god
Music is Despair.
上帝
God
音乐是欲望。
god
Music is Desire.
音乐是疯狂的。
Music is Insanity.
音乐是黑暗。
Music is Darkness.
在堕落天使的歌声中死去。
Die, by the songs of fallen angels.
超级黑暗天使，Yami_Q_ray！
Super Dark Angels, Yami_Q_ray!
Yami_Q_ray？！
Yami_Q_ray?!
现在认真地招待我？
Now entertain me
Seriously?
这个世界太无聊了，
This world is so boring,
我太失望了
I'm so disillusioned
我会拿走你的一切
I'll take everything from you
你所有的爱，
All your love,
梦想，
dreams,
音乐
music,
和希望
and hope
没有人会听到你
No one will hear you
没有人会听到您100%的功率输出。
Power output at 100%.
来吧，打破它
警报器系统已经唤醒。
Come on, break it
The Siren System has awakened.
来吧，打破它
Come on, break it
来吧，打破它。
So it's done.
来吧，打破它
Come on, break it
分成小块。你的身体，
Into little pieces. Your body,
你的生命，你的一切
your life, your all
你的生活，你所有的文化结构都出现了
Pro to culture structures have appeared
你的生命，你的一切
your life, your all
你的生命，你的全部，除了文德米尔和拉格纳！
on both Windermere and Ragna!
在温德米尔和拉格纳！
On both Windermere and Ragna!
我对感情不感兴趣，文德米尔和拉格纳都不感兴趣！
I'm not interested in feelings,
on both Windermere and Ragna!
我对感觉不感兴趣，
I'm not interested in feelings,
我对感觉不感兴趣，什么？！
What?!
我对感觉不感兴趣，
I'm not interested in feelings,
我对感情不感兴趣，他们也喜欢沃尔多和阿尔海姆！
I'm not interested in feelings, They've
appeared on Voldor and Alfheim as well!
他们也出现在沃尔多和阿尔海姆上！
They've appeared on Voldor
and Alfheim as well!
我会毁了一切的。他们已经出现了\非沃尔多和阿尔海姆！
I'll wreck it all They've appeared
on Voldor and Alfheim as well!
我会毁了一切
I'll wreck it all
我会毁了一切，超级铁门开始形成了。
I'll wreck it all A Super
Fold Gate is starting to form.
我会毁了一切
I'll wreck it all
我会毁掉一切的他们用深入的学习
They used deep learning to
他们利用深度学习
开始了-毁灭了-结束的声音
T他们用深入的学习
It's begun -Destroy- The sound of the end
They used deep learning to
开始了-毁灭了-结束的声音
It's begun -Destroy- The sound of the end
它开始了-毁灭了-结束的声音
复制了《黑暗歌手》，
It's begun -Destroy- The sound of the end
create copies of the Singer of the Dark,
开始了-毁灭了-结束的声音
It's begun -Destroy- The sound of the end
它开始了——毁灭了——结束的声音——增强了他们的歌唱能力。
amplifying their singing power.
增强他们的歌唱能力。
Amplifying their singing power.
已经响起，别挡着我的路。增强他们的歌唱能力。
Has rung out, don't get in my way
amplifying their singing power.
已经挂断电话了，别挡我的路
Has rung out, don't get in my way
已经挂断电话了，别挡我的路，他们来了！所有单位，近距离作战！
has rung out, don't get in my way Here they
come! All units, engage at close range!
像天使一样，从你D.N.A的角度来看
Like an Angel, from the
depths of your D.N.A
唱毁灭之歌，就像你在尖叫
Sing devastation, like you're screaming
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。邪恶的船体被攻破了！
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil
The hull's been breached!
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。恶毒的
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。邪恶
Shit！
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil
Shit!
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。恶毒的
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。邪恶的追逐！
Giving chase!
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。恶毒的
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil
在内心深处，你一定也希望如此
Deep inside, you must be wishing it too
但否认。否认说谎者。你仍然
But deny. Deny. Liar. You still
似乎疼痛还不够
haven't had enough pain, it seems
疼痛还不够，似乎
NEnemy战斗机正在进站！
haven't had enough pain, it seems
Enemy fighters inbound!
似乎疼痛不够
Haven't had enough pain, it seems
还没有经历足够的痛苦，似乎不要跌倒\后退！破坏者中队，行动起来拦截！
haven't had enough pain, it seems Do not fall
back! Destroid squadrons, move to intercept!
不要后退！毁灭者中队，行动起来拦截！
Do not fall back! Destroid
squadrons, move to intercept!
消失就是狂喜
Perishing is ecstasy
该死！别再胡闹了！
Dammit! Quit buzzing around!
海亚特！
Hayate!
让我们再玩一些
Let's play some more
这还远远不够
This isn't nearly enough
这还不够
T他们在捣乱我们！
This isn't nearly enough
They're messing with us!
这还远远不够
This isn't nearly enough
很接近，
It's close,
Freyja！
Freyja!
星座
The constellation
每30年才来一次
that comes but once every 30 years
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
我不想睡着
I don't want to fall asleep
直到我看到它和你在一起
until I see it with you
!/ 感觉齿轮转动
!/ feel the gears turning
慢点，慢点什么？！
slowly, slowly
What?!
慢慢地，慢慢地
Slowly, slowly
弗雷亚。。。
Freyja...
你有没有想过有多少秒
Have you ever wondered how many seconds
你有没有想过Fre有多少秒！
Fre-Fre!
你有没有想过有多少秒
Have you ever wondered how many seconds
No-Freyja，不要！
No Freyja, don't!
一年后，
Are in a year,
一天，一刻？
a day, a moment?
现在别告诉我，我甚至不想知道
Don't tell me now, I don't even wanna know
下一颗彗星什么时候会来
when the next comet will come
现在不要告诉我，即使这是结局，
Don't tell me now, even if this is the end,
现在不要告诉我，即使这已经结束了，
那动作，发生了什么？！
Don't tell me now, even if this is the end,
That maneuver, what's going on?!
现在不要告诉我，即使这是结局，
Don't tell me now, even if this is the end,
现在不要告诉我，即使这是结束，
Hayate！
Don't tell me now, even if this is the end,
Hayate!
现在不要告诉我，即使这是结局，
Don't tell me now, even if this is the end,
我不想后悔
I don't want to regret it
所有部队，撤离！
All forces, evacuate!
风开始刮了
The wind starts to blow
没有警告
without warning
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
发生了什么？
What's happening?
现在
Now!
今晚别让我失望
Don't let me down, tonight
我会找到那个星座
I'll find that constellation
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
马十字旗Gigasion已经紧急关闭。
The Ma cross Gigasion has
executed an emergency Fold.
嗯，似乎有一个带警报器系统的Nissue？
Hmm, seems there's an
issue with the Siren System?
这不是问题。
It's not a problem.
我们成功地生成了与所有五个成员相同的Bio Fold
Waves
We succeeded in generating Bio-Fold
Waves equal to that of all five members
Walkure与一个人的脑细胞计数相结合。
of Walkure combined with the
brain cell count of a single person.
你看，
And look,
我们已经占领了所有拥有Pro to文化遗址的星球。
we've seized all the planets
that have Pro to culture ruins.
现在我们可以开门了
Now we can open
银河系任何地方的超级折叠门。
Super Fold Gates anywhere in the galaxy.
资助罗伊德·布雷姆的研究确实获得了很好的回报。
Funding Roid Brehm's research
has paid off very well indeed.
首先你帮助了温德米尔人，现在你在帮助我们。。。
First you aided the Windermerians,
now you're helping us...
真聪明。
How clever.
嗯，你们都是我们的宝贵客户。
Well, you're both our
valued customers.
增强感官意识？
Enhanced sensory awareness?
感觉到Hayate有危险，
Sensing Hayate was in danger,
Freyja的生物折叠波\增强到最大。
Freyja's Bio-Fold Waves
intensified to the max.
这使得他的Fold Quartz与Fre Fre的演唱产生共鸣，
This caused his Fold Quartz to
resonate with Fre-Fre's singing,
增强哈亚·哈亚的感官和能力。
enhancing Haya-Haya's senses and abilities.
所以这让他发疯了。。。
So it made him go berserk...
这是我的错…她是这样的。
It's my fault... she's like this.
唱歌…是…我的。。。
Singing... is... my...
Freyja，我要带你离开任务。
Freyja, I'm taking you off the mission.
不
No...
一个连自己都站不住的人
Someone who can't even
stand on their own
将成为战场上的障碍。
will be a hindrance on the battlefield.
所以你现在就休息一下。
So you just rest for now.
放松点，我们将夺回
Windermere和Ragna。
Relax, we'll take back
Windermere and Ragna.
然后我们将举行一个有水母和苹果的聚会。
Then we'll have a party
with jellyfish and apples.
扔出
Chuck...
这里，弗雷弗雷。。。
Here, Fre-Fre...
这是哈亚·哈亚拯救的苹果的种子。
It's a seed from the apple
that Haya-Haya saved.
你应该把它带回温德米尔。
You should bring it back to Windermere.
好吧。
Alrighty.
Freyja再也不会唱歌了？
Freyja can't sing anymore?
你这是什么意思？！
What do you mean by that?!
你看到她变得多么虚弱了。。。
You saw how weak she's become...
她不太可能再承受增强型生物折叠波的压力了。。。
It's unlikely she can take the strain
of enhanced Bio-Fold Waves anymore...
她不能治好吗？
Can't she be cured?
结晶……不是一种疾病。
Crystallization... isn't a disease.
她的细胞受损严重。
The damage to her cells is severe.
即使她停止了，伤害也已经结束了。。。
Even if she stops, the
damage has been done...
“闪耀过亮的符文会缩短人的寿命……”
“A rune that shines too bright
can shorten one's life..."
这就是约翰神父的意思。
So this is what Father Johann meant.
国王陛下的身体也变白了。
The whitening of the body happened
to His Majesty the King as well.
那么，如果她不唱歌，情况不会变得更糟吗？
So, if she doesn't sing,
it won't get worse?
我不知道。但她不能在战场上唱歌。。。
I don't know. But she
can't sing on battlefield...
Walkire届时将和你们四个人一起完成任务。这不容易。。。
Walkire will do the mission with just
four of you then. It won't be easy...
我们会完成这项工作的。
We'll get the job done.
如果我们能干扰敌人的歌唱。。。
If we can somehow jam
the enemy's singing...
让我们马上开始。
Let's get started right away.
可以
Okay.
米库莫？
Mikumo?
一、 …想唱歌。。。！
I... want to sing...!
和Freyja…再次和你，Freyja。。。
With Freyja... With you again, Freyja...
米库莫。。。
Mikumo...
战争期间，当事情变得艰难时，音乐帮助我度过了难关。
When things got rough during the war,
music helped get me through it.
这就是为什么我总是尊敬瓦尔库尔。\你用音乐保护人们。
That's why I always looked up to Walkure.
You protect people with music.
别担心。无论发生什么，我都会。。。
Don't worry. No matter what happens, I'll...
永远是Walkure，好吗？
always be a Walkure, okay?
弗雷亚。。。
Freyja...
/时间太长了，马西米兰酋长。
/It's been too long,
Commander-in-Chief Maximilian.
我们都很高兴能再次与您并肩作战。
We're all excited to
fight beside you again.
荣誉属于我。我指望着你。
The honor is mine. I'm counting on you.
阿拉德指挥官，我们的计划是什么？
Commander Arad, what's our plan?
下次敌人打开折叠门时，
The next time the enemy
opens their Fold gates,
我们将穿过其中一个
攻击温德米尔。
we'll go through one of them
and attack Windermere.
这可能吗？
Is that possible?
我们已经根据非指挥官阿拉德的提议制定了一个打击计划。
We've devised a strike plan based
on Commander Arad's proposal.
我们相信，如果我们
We believe it to be possible if we
使用Walkure的Bio Fold Waves提升我们船的折叠驱动力。
boost the Fold drives of our ships
with Walkure's Bio-Fold Waves.
我们相信，在任何一个拥有Pro to文化遗址的星球上，都可以打开大门。
We believe the gates can be opened on
any planet with Pro to culture ruins.
离我们当前位置最近的是。。。
The nearest one to our
current position is...
阿尔海姆星球。
Planet Alfheim.
我们应该能够利用小行星带作为掩护，潜入而不被发现。
We should be able to sneak in undetected
by using the asteroid belt as cover.
卡内小姐，有什么不对劲吗？
Is there something wrong, Miss Kaname?
没有，先生。
No sir.
一位倒下的战友在美国东北部服役时曾驻扎在那个星球上。
A fallen comrade used to be stationed on
that planet when he served in N.U.N.S.
它勒费尔德先生。
It. Messer lhlefeld.
所有手到战斗站/
Repeat，所有手到作战站/
All hands to battle stations/
Repeat, all hands to battle stations/
全体上阵！
All hands to battle stations/!
我飞行指挥官？
Me? Flight commander?
我不能。我们需要你来领导我们，阿拉德指挥官！
I can't. We need you to
lead us, Commander Arad!
从桥上我只能做这么多。
There's only so much I
can do from the bridge.
没事的。你可以做到。
It'll be okay. You can do it.
做你自己。在你自己的天空中飞翔。
Just be yourself. Fly in your own sky.
飞…在我自己的天空。。。
Fly... in my own sky...
海亚特。
Hayate.
先生
Sir.
很抱歉，没有告诉你。
Sorry for not telling you
about your father.
没关系。但我从没想过他在温德米尔。
It's alright. But I never would've
guessed he was on Windermere.
我改天再告诉你更多关于他的事。
I'll tell you more about him some other time.
至少是对孩子友好的故事。
The kid-friendly stories, at least.
是的，请这样做。
Yes, please do.
那么，你没有地方可去吗？
Well, don't you have
somewhere to be?
嗯？
Huh?
手术前剩下的时间不多了。
Not much time left before the operation.
是的……谢谢你，先生。
Yes... Thank you sir.
弗雷亚。。。
Freyja...
那个该死的女孩。。。
That darn girl...
必须快点。。。
Gotta hurry...
别傻了！你想唱歌吗？！在你的情况下？
Don't be a fool! You're gonna
try to sing?! In your condition?
我应该是Walkire！
I'm supposed to be a Walkire!
我本应该是Walkure，但。。。
I'm supposed to be a Walkure, but...
我说，“不管发生什么”，但是。。。
I said, "no matter what happens," but...
为什么我…我害怕。。。
Why am I... I'm scared...
我不敢唱歌。
I'm afraid to sing.
我害怕死！
I'm scared of dying!
我应该是Walkure。
A Walkure应该通过唱歌来保护每个人。
I'm supposed to be a Walkure.
A Walkure's supposed to protect everyone by singing.
但我不能…我不会唱歌。
But I can't... I can't sing.
我好害怕。。。
I'm so scared...
我恐怕我不能再和你在一起了！
I-I'm afraid I won't be able
to be with you anymore!
弗雷亚。。。
Freyja...
我该怎么办？
What should I do?
我该怎么办，海亚特？
What should I do, Hayate?
你必须停止唱歌。
You have to stop singing.
那我就不再是Walkure了。
Then I'll no longer be a Walkure.
海亚特，你能不飞而活吗？
Can you live without flying, Hayate?
我会保护温德米尔！我保证。
I'll protect Windermere! I promise.
所以我想让你活着。
So I want you to live.
我要你继续活下去！
I want you to live on!
我想和你一起生活。
I want to live my life with you.
我也是。。。
So do I...
我也想和你在一起，海亚特。
I want to be with you too, Hayate.
但是
But...
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
你和我，我保证。。。
You and me, I promise...
在沉默中淡出
Fade away in silence
（！喜欢独处）
(! prefer being alone)
黑暗太深了
Darkness is so much
比光更美
more beautiful than light
那么你想保护什么？
So what are you trying to protect?
你内心如此脆弱，你会
You're so weak inside, you'll
你自己打碎
break into pieces yourself
我们是来解放银河系的
We're here to free the galaxy
正在播放旋律我们来这里是为了解放银河系
A melody is playing
We're here to free the galaxy
正在播放旋律
A melody is playing
一首曲子正在演奏，是M女士为了阻止我们的人类文明，
A melody is playing of Lady M, who
intends to prevent our human civilization,
打算阻止我们人类文明的M女士，
of Lady M, who intends to
prevent our human civilization,
请仔细听M女士说，她打算阻止我们的人类文明，
Listen closely of Lady M, who intends
to prevent our human civilization,
仔细听
Listen closely
仔细聆听进化。
from evolving.
从进化开始。
From evolving.
这是不可避免的命运……来自进化。
It's inescapable destiny...
from evolving.
这是不可避免的命运。。。
It's inescapable destiny...
这是不可逃避的命运……时机已经成熟！
The time has come to rise!
这是不可避免的命运。。。
It's inescapable destiny...
这是不可避免的命运……部署所有部队！
Deploy all forces!
开始了-毁灭了-结束的声音
It's begun -Destroy- The sound of the end
已经挂断电话了，别挡我的路
has rung out, don't get in my way
像天使一样，从你的D.N.A深处
Like an Angel, from the depths of your D.N.A
唱毁灭之歌，就像你在尖叫
Sing devastation, like you're screaming
唱毁灭性的歌，就像你在尖叫一样。正如所料，在联合国军队中没有发生叛乱行为。
Sing devastation, like you're screaming As expected, acts
of insurrection have broken out within N.U.N.S. ranks.
唱毁灭之歌，就像你在尖叫
Sing devastation, like you're screaming
唱“毁灭”，就像你在尖叫一样。以这种速度，它很可能会导致
At this rate, it may well lead to
以这种速度，很可能导致
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。邪恶以这种速度，很可能导致
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil
At this rate, it may well lead to
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。恶毒的
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。邪恶\横扫银河系的战争。
all-out war across the galaxy.
在内心深处，你一定已经知道，我们会在这之前干掉克伦威尔。
Deep inside, you must already know We'll
take out Cromwell before that happens.
在内心深处，你一定已经知道了
Deep inside, you must already know
在内心深处，你一定已经知道进入阿尔海姆的防守范围。
Entering Alfheim's defense perimeter.
但否认。否认说谎者。您仍在启动Jormungandr行动！
But deny. Deny. Liar. You still
Commencing Operation Jormungandr!
但否认。否认说谎者。你仍然
But deny. Deny. Liar. You still
似乎疼痛还不够。
haven't had enough pain, it seems.
恶毒的恶毒的我是邪恶的。恶毒的
Evil. Evil. I am evil. Evil
-它不会停止，
-堕落天使的歌声
-It won't stop,
-the song of fallen angels
-现在，我将吞没所有人
-Now all
-will I engulf
-现在，我将吞没所有的发射/突击队战士！
-Now all -will I engulf Launch
all assault team fighters!
启动所有突击队战士！
Launch all assault team fighters!
来吧。一个黑暗而冰冷的世界
L发射所有突击队战士！
Come on. A dark and frozen world
Launch all assault team fighters!
来吧，一个黑暗而冰冷的世界
Come on. A dark and frozen world
来吧。一个黑暗而冰冷的世界。你当上了幻影飞行指挥官？
You made Mirage flight commander?
你被任命为幻影飞行指挥官？
! 会给你看你做的幻影飞行指挥官吗？
! will show you
You made Mirage flight commander?
你被任命为幻影飞行指挥官？
深渊你做了幻影飞行指挥官？
The abyss
You made Mirage flight commander?
深渊
The abyss
深渊\耐心，你会看到的。
Patience, you'll see.
深渊
The abyss
海亚特。。。
Hayate...
我明白了。
I get it.
我不可能马上接替Messer的职位。
There's no way I can fill
Messer's shoes right away.
但我仍然想像他那样保护人们。
But still, I want to protect
people like he did.
所以娃娃。
So doll.
白色骑士。。。
White Knight...
他只是说我们都有同样的感觉，深红骑士！
He's just saying we all feel
the same, Crimson Knight!
我收到了我的命令。我将被调到拉雷米系统。
I received my orders. I'm to be
transferred to the Laramie System.
哦
Oh.
银河系的那一部分仍然没有受到Var综合征的影响，这是安全的。
Well that part of the galaxy is still
untouched by the Var Syndrome, it's safe.
所以，你将成为那里的一名飞行员。祝你好运好吗？
So, you're going to be a flight
instructor there. Good luck okay?
非常感谢。
Thank you.
看来我可以带上我的瓦尔基里了。
It looks like I'll be able to take
my Valkyrie with me.
尽管/|怀疑我们会看到更多的实战。
Although /| doubt we'll see
any more actual combat.
即便如此，我还是会继续飞行，卡内姆小姐。
Even so, I'll keep flying Miss Kaname.
Messer。。。
Messer...
然后我也会继续唱歌。
Then I'll keep singing too.
梅瑟，指引我们。
Messer, guide us.
我再也跟不上了
I could never keep up
你总是
You were always
看着外面的东西
Looking out at something
从这个地方
from this place
算上那些事情，
Counting those things that,
一旦着魔，
once possessed,
一旦拥有，超级折叠
门同步成功！
once possessed, Super Fold
Gate synchronization successful!
超级折叠门
synchronization成功！
Super Fold Gate
synchronization successful!
超级折叠门丢失
同步成功！
Are lost Super Fold Gate
synchronization successful!
都迷路了
Are lost
所有部队都被消灭了，快进！
are lost
All forces, move in!
都迷路了
Are lost
你藏着眼泪，
You were hiding your tears,
你在掩饰眼泪，
课程调整完成。
You were hiding your tears,
Fleet course adjustment complete.
车队路线调整完成。
你不是吗？
Fleet航线调整完成。
Weren't you?
Fleet course adjustment complete.
你不是吗？
Weren't you?
所有船只，全速前进！
All ships, full speed ahead!
那么强烈
That intense
你的凝视
gaze of yours
您的凝视
Super Fold成功！
gaze of yours
Super Fold successful!
看到了这个世界
Saw the world
看到了世界
Delta Flight，离开！
Saw the world
Delta Flight, move out!
看到了这个世界
Saw the world
在不同的光线下
in a different light
梦想
Dreams
Enemy舰队已进入系统。
Enemy fleet has entered the system.
没有人能单独到达他们已经通过了超级折叠门！
Aren't reached alone
They've come through the Super Fold Gate!
无法独自接触
Aren't reached alone
没有人能单独联系到他们。唉，太晚了！
aren't reached alone
Heh, they're too late!
它们乘着看不见的风向我们飞来
They fly to us on invisible winds
消失就是狂喜
Perishing is ecstasy
另一扇门？！
Another gate?!
它似乎与子空间相连。
It seems to be connected to subspace.
使用折叠雷达扫描。
Scanning with Fold Radar.
让我们用折叠雷达进行更多的扫描。
Let's play some more
Scanning with Fold Radar.
让我们再玩一些
Let's play some more
让我们多玩一些游戏
T这是。。。！
Let's play some more
That's...!
让我们再玩一些
Let's play some more
这还远远不够
This isn't nearly enough
不知道您是否可以联系到我
The Megaroad-01！
Wonder if you can reach me
The Megaroad-01!
不知道你能不能联系到我
Wonder if you can reach me
不知道你能否联系到我。时间到了！
The time has come!
时间到了！
（来吧，到这里来）时间到了！
(Come on, over here)
The time has come!
（来吧，这边）
(Come on, over here)
（来吧，到这里来）现在我们将实现我们为之奋斗的目标！
(Come on, over here) Now we will achieve
what we have fought for all this time!
现在，我们将实现我们为之奋斗的目标！
Now we will achieve what we
have fought for all this time!
让我看到你在挣扎，听到你在哭泣。现在，我们将实现我们为之奋斗的目标！
Let me see you struggle, hear you wail Now we will
achieve what we have fought for all this time!
让我看到你挣扎，听到你哭泣
Let me see you struggle, hear you wail
继续，休息
Go on, break
伪君子天真的笑容
The innocent smile of hypocrites
保护M女士！
Protect Lady M!
伪君子天真的笑容
The innocent smile of hypocrites
Commence Operation Silence！
Commence Operation Silence!
开始沉默行动！
这是一个罪恶的梦
Commence Operation Silence！
ls a sinful dream
Commence Operation Silence!
是一个罪恶的梦
ls a sinful dream
是一个罪恶的梦-罗杰！\噢，先生！
is a sinful dream - Roger!
- Oorah sir!
是一个罪恶的梦
ls a sinful dream
应收账
AR
因此，他们的策略是干扰所有Fold-NWave，甚至他们自己的歌曲。
So their strategy is to jam all Fold
Waves, even their own songs.
折叠干扰成功。。。
Fold Jamming successful...
请记住，Walkure的演唱在干扰期间也会失去效果。
Remember that Walkure's singing will
also lose its effect during jamming.
让我们快点！
Let's make this quick!
三角洲5号，不要破坏队形！
Delta 5, don't break formation!
三角洲3号，三点钟的强盗。。。
Delta 3, the bandit at three o'clock...
不，跟着塔纳托斯队形走！
No, go with the Thanatos formation!
抓紧，幻影！
Get a grip, Mirage!
在干扰有效的时候，我们会干掉他们！
We'll take them out while
the jamming is effective!
所有部队，准备
跨炮发射！
All forces, prepare for
Ma cross Cannon discharge!
所有船舶开始改造。
All ships commencing transformation.
连接动力传输系统
Connecting power transfer system
他们的歌声。。。
Their singing...
我听不到他们的歌声。。。
I can't hear their singing...
所有战士都要立即清除火线。
All fighters are to clear the
line of fire immediately.
我重复一遍，所有战士都要立即清除火线。
I repeat, all fighters are to clear
the line of fire immediately.
能源费为130%。
Energy charge at 130%.
所有船只，开火吧！
All ships, fire your Ma cross Cannons!
他们的屏障被加固了。
Their barrier's been reinforced.
干扰系统。。。
The jamming system's...
被反击了！
been countered!
这就是
Siren系统的力量。壮丽的
So this is the power of the
Siren System. Magnificent!
Walkure对我们没有任何用处。
Walkure is of no further use to us.
摧毁他们！消灭那些被诅咒的M女士女神！
Destroy them! Wipe out those
accursed goddesses of Lady M!
（倾倒）反正你们现在都是奴隶
(Pouring) You're all slaves now anyway
（倾倒）无论如何，你们现在都是奴隶。超级折叠门又出现了！
The Super Fold Gates are reappearing!
超级折叠门又出现了！
（咬）装酷没有用，没有没有，超级折叠门又出现了！
(Biting) No use pretending to be cool, no no
no no The Super Fold Gates are reappearing!
（咬）装酷没用，不不不不
(Biting) No use pretending to be cool,
no no no no
（咬）假装酷没有用，没有没有没有没有这个角度！
(Biting) No use pretending to
be cool, no no no no This angle!
（懒惰）我的意思是，你把握得对吗？
这太糟糕了！
(Lazy) I mean, you're holding it right?
This is bad!
（懒惰）我的意思是，你把握得对吗？
(Lazy) I mean, you're holding it right?
他们的火力线因
Their line of fire has shifted due to
（懒惰）我的意思是，你把握得对吗？
(Lazy) I mean, you're holding it right?
Windermere的行星自转！
Windermere's planetary rotation!
温德米尔的行星旋转！
地狱邀请
Windermere行星自转！
An invitation to hell
Windermere's planetary rotation!
下地狱的邀请
An invitation to hell
如果他们用他们的
An invitation to hell If they
fire on the Megaroad-01 with their
如果他们用他们的
If they fire on
the Megaroad-01 with their
（羞愧）我想这是死胡同，如果他们用他们的
(Abashed) It's a dead end, I reckon If
they fire on the Megaroad-01 with their
（羞愧）我想这是个死胡同
(Abashed) It's a dead end, I reckon
（羞愧地）这是一条死胡同，我想
从那个位置出发的马越大炮。。。
(Abashed) It's a dead end, I reckon
Hyper Ma cross Cannon from that position...
超马十字炮从那个位置。。。
（湿漉漉的）你是一群即兴木筏，甚至站在那个位置上的超马十字炮。。。
(Soggy) You're a bunch of riff raft, even standing
still Hyper Ma cross Cannon from that position...
（湿漉漉的）你真是一堆废话，尼文一动不动
(Soggy) You're a bunch of riff raft,
even standing still
（湿漉漉的）你是一堆废话木筏，站着不动的奈文，温德米尔会。。。
(Soggy) You're a bunch of riff raft,
even standing still Windermere will be...
温德米尔将。。。
Windermere will be...
（哎哟）转眼间，这个世界就变成了。。。
(Ouch) In an instant, this world becomes
Windermere will be...
（哎哟）转眼间，这个世界变得
(Ouch) In an instant, this world becomes
猥亵的监狱
an indecent prison
但是，但是，但是你
But, but, but you
但是，但是，但是你什么？！
What?!
但是，但是，但是你
But, but, but you
忘记了这一点
oblivious to this
忘了这难道没有办法阻止他们开火吗？！
oblivious to this Isn't there
some way to stop them from firing?!
对虚假的爱情欣喜若狂这是摧毁飞船内部系统的唯一方法！
Are ecstatic over a fake love The only way
is to destroy the system inside their ship!
对虚假的爱情欣喜若狂
Are ecstatic over a fake love
对虚假的爱情欣喜若狂，但如何？
are ecstatic over a fake love
But how?
对虚假的爱情欣喜若狂
Are ecstatic over a fake love
在Walkire的歌声中，为一段虚假的爱情而欣喜若狂！
are ecstatic over a fake love
With Walkire's singing!
燃烧、拥抱、哭泣、后悔
就是这样！如果我们提高
Burn, embrace, cry, regret
That's it! If we boost our
燃烧、拥抱、哭泣、后悔
Burn, embrace, cry, regret
用我们的歌声燃烧、拥抱、哭泣、后悔lil'
Kairos Plus'的力量。。。
Burn, embrace, cry, regret lil'
Kairos Plus' power with our singing...
lil“Kairos Plus”的力量
伴随着我们的歌唱。。。
lil' Kairos Plus' power
with our singing...
用我们的歌声粉碎我，吸吮我小小的‘Kairos
Plus’力量。。。
Shatter me, suck on me lil' Kairos
Plus' power with our singing...
粉碎我，吮吸我
Shatter me, suck on me
粉碎我，吸吮我它可能会冲破他们的维度障碍。
Shatter me, suck on me It might be able
to break through their dimensional barrier.
它可能能够突破他们的维度障碍。
It might be able to break through
their dimensional barrier.
破坏了我，它可能能够突破他们的维度障碍。
Corrupt me It might be able to break
through their dimensional barrier.
毁了我
Corrupt me
到了我骨子里
to the very marrow of my bones
愤怒，麻痹，迷恋，溺水
Writhe, be paralyzed, be mesmerized, drown
来找我
Come to me
来找我-反作用弹头！
-收到多个热信号！
Come to me - Reaction warheads!
- Multiple heat signatures incoming!
所有部队从三点钟的高度拦截来袭的导弹。
All forces, intercept incoming
missiles from three o'clock high.
防止他们袭击主力舰队！
Prevent them from hitting the main fleet!
罗杰/
Roger/
他们成功了！
They got though!
我们还没做完！
We ain't done yet!
向右舷升起定点障碍物！
Raise Pinpoint Barriers to starboard!
全体人员，做好准备迎接冲击！
All hands, brace for impact!
曾经如此贪婪地诱惑过。多可爱啊
So greedy once seduced. How cute
曾经如此贪婪地诱惑过。多么可爱啊，她仍然完好无损！
Whew, she's still intact!
哟，她还完好无损！
如果每个人都是英雄，那真是太无聊了。哎呀，她还完好无损！
ltd be such a bore if everyone
were a hero Whew, she's still intact!
如果每个人都是英雄，那就太无聊了
ltd be such a bore if
everyone were a hero
如果每个人都是英雄的话，那就太令人讨厌了。主炮75%装药。
ltd be such a bore if everyone
were a hero Main guns at 75% charge.
如果每个人都是英雄，那就太无聊了
ltd be such a bore if
everyone were a hero
如果每个人都是英雄，那就太无聊了不！
ltd be such a bore if
everyone were a hero No!
如果我们不阻止他们，Megaroad-01将。。。
If we don't stop them, Megaroad-01 will...
渴望、聚敛、崇拜、崇拜
Lady M将。。。！
Yearn, amass, idolize, worship
Lady M will...!
渴望、聚敛、崇拜、崇拜
Yearn, amass, idolize, worship
渴望、聚集、崇拜、崇拜
Windermere will。。。！
Yearn, amass, idolize, worship
Windermere will...!
渴望、聚敛、崇拜、崇拜
Yearn, amass, idolize, worship
渴望、聚敛、崇拜、崇拜银河系的平衡将被摧毁！
Yearn, amass, idolize, worship The
balance of the galaxy will be destroyed!
燃烧、拥抱、哭泣、后悔
Burn, embrace, cry, regret
粉碎我，吮吸我
Shatter me, suck on me
腐败我
corrupt me
毁了我，毁了你！
Damn you!
该死的你！
为了我的骨子里的你！
To the very marrow of my bones
Damn you!
到了我骨子里
To the very marrow of my bones
到了我骨子里，在你身后！
to the very marrow of my bones
Delta 6, behind you!
到了我骨子里
To the very marrow of my bones
你以为我纯洁、洁白、干净
You thought I was pure, white and clean
不是吗？
Didn't you?
不是吗？\纳亚特·伊梅尔曼！
Hayate Immelmann!
海亚特·伊梅尔曼！
那不行。美丽的花朵是
Hayate Immelmann！
That won't do. Pretty flowers are
Hayate Immelmann!
那不行。漂亮的花是
That won't do. Pretty flowers are
那不行。美丽的花朵是我誓言要保卫温德米尔！
I vow to defend Windermere!
那不行。漂亮的花是
That won't do. Pretty flowers are
那不行。美丽的花朵是善良的人在那里，苹果园，我会保护他们！
That won't do. Pretty flowers are The kind people
there, the apple orchards, I'll defend them all!
那里善良的人们，苹果\诺查兹，我会保护他们所有人！
The kind people there, the apple
orchards, I'll defend them all!
有毒，我告诉你。（邪恶得发疯）那里善良的人，苹果园，我会保护他们所有人！
Poisonous, I tell you. (Go mad with wickedness) The kind
people there, the apple orchards, I'll defend them all!
有毒，告诉你。
（因邪恶而疯狂）
Poisonous, / tell you.
(Go mad with wickedness)
有毒，告诉你。（疯狂邪恶）总有一天，我会摆脱
Poisonous, / tell you. (Go mad
with wickedness) And one day, I'll rid
总有一天，我会摆脱
And one day, I'll rid
夜以继日地跳舞。（爱得发狂）总有一天，我会摆脱
Dance, night and day. (Go mad
with love) And one day, I'll rid
夜以继日地跳舞。
（爱得发狂）
Dance, night and day.
(Go mad with love)
夜以继日地跳舞。（用爱发疯）所有战争的银河系！
Dance, night and day. (Go mad
with love) the galaxy of all war!
夜以继日地跳舞。
（爱得发狂）
Dance, night and day.
(Go mad with love)
这种毒药很厉害。（在黑暗中发疯）然后Freyja可以
The poison is potent. (Go mad
with darkness) Then Freyja can
这种毒药很厉害。
（在黑暗中发疯）
The poison is potent.
(Go mad with darkness)
这种毒药很厉害。（发疯了）再次和瓦尔库尔一起唱！
The poison is potent. (Go mad with
darkness) sing with Walkure again!
再和瓦库尔一起唱歌！
Sing with Walkure again!
日夜歌唱。是 啊\又和瓦尔库尔一起唱了！
Sing, night and day. Yeah!
sing with Walkure again!
日夜歌唱。是 啊
Sing, night and day. Yeah!
Haya Haya。。。
Haya-Haya...
日夜歌唱。是 啊
Sing, night and day. Yeah!
日夜歌唱。是 啊\每一天，温柔的歌曲。
Everyday, tender songs.
每天，温柔的歌声。
有毒，我告诉你。（疯狂于邪恶）每天，温柔的歌曲。
Poisonous, I tell you. (Go mad with
wickedness) Everyday, tender songs.
有毒，我告诉你。
（因邪恶而疯狂）
Poisonous, I tell you.
(Go mad with wickedness)
有毒，我告诉你。（疯狂于邪恶）不是为了停止战争。
Poisonous, I tell you. (Go mad with
wickedness) Not for stopping wars.
夜以继日地跳舞。
（爱得发狂）
Dance, night and day.
(Go mad with love)
夜以继日地跳舞。（疯狂的爱）三角洲航班可以飞翔天空，
Dance, night and day. (Go mad with
love) And Delta Flight can fly the skies,
Delta Flight可以飞上天空，
And Delta Flight can fly the skies,
我告诉你，这种毒药很厉害。（对黑暗发疯）三角洲航班可以飞翔天空，
The poison is potent I tell you. (Go mad with
darkness) And Delta Flight can fly the skies,
我告诉你，这种毒药很厉害。
（在黑暗中发疯）
The poison is potent I tell you.
(Go mad with darkness)
我告诉你，这种毒药很厉害。（在黑暗中疯狂）跟着他们的歌。
The poison is potent I tell you. (Go
mad with darkness) along to their song.
我告诉你，这种毒药很厉害。
（在黑暗中发疯）
The poison is potent I tell you.
(Go mad with darkness)
我告诉你，这种毒药很厉害。
（在黑暗中发疯）海亚特。。。
The poison is potent I tell you.
(Go mad with darkness) Hayate...
日夜歌唱。是 啊\我们会活下去的。
Sing, night and day. Yeah!
We'll live life.
日夜歌唱。是 啊
Sing, night and day. Yeah!
日夜歌唱。是 啊\我们一起唱。一起飞翔。
We'll sing together. Fly together.
我们一起唱。一起飞翔。
戒毒是徒劳的，我们一起唱。一起飞翔。
Detoxification is futile
We'll sing together. Fly together.
戒毒是徒劳的
Detoxification is futile
戒毒是徒劳的我们会一起生活！
Detoxification ls futile
We'll live life together!
戒毒是徒劳的
Detoxification is futile
海亚特。。。
Hayate...
歌曲和风，一起。。。
Both song and wind, together...
不会放弃，不会放弃，
Won't give up, won't give up,
Freyja？！
Freyja?!
不会放弃，
Won't give up,
我是Freyja。
It's Freyja.
永远不会
Never ever
现在，现在，现在。。。
Now, now, now,
That voice...
现在，现在，现在，
Now, now, now,
现在，现在，现在
不可能。。。
Now, now, now,
No way...
我能听到某人的声音
I can hear someone's voice
-弗雷亚！
-氟利昂！
- Freyja!
- Fre-Fre!
Freyja，不要！
Freyja, don't!
你必须躺在床上！
You've got to stay in bed!
“你活着是为了什么？你唱歌是为了什么……”
"For what do you live?
For what do you sing..."
对不起，约翰神父。
I'm sorry, Father Johann.
对不起，海亚特。。。
Sorry, Hayate...
但我要唱歌了。
But I'm going to sing.
因为我是Walkire！
Because I'm a Walkire!
Freyja，你。。。
Freyja, you...
但在你的州。。。
But in your state...
我想和你一起生活，Kaname！
I want to live life,
together with you Kaname!
还有米库莫。
And Mikumo.
还有马基纳。
And Makina.
还有雷纳。
And Reina.
我想和每个人一起生活。
I want to live life
together with everyone.
“想要生活。。。
"Want to live life...
在一起
Together...
与每个人“？
With everyone"?
对我来说，生活意味着
To me, living means
像Walkure一样唱歌！
singing as a Walkure!
我想继续和你们大家一起散步！
I want to continue living
as a Walkure with you all!
我没有退缩！不在生活中，不在唱歌，不在……爱中。
I'm not holding back! Not on life,
not on singing, not on... love.
没有退缩。。。
Not holding back...
我要活下去。把我的生命活到尽头。
I想要绝对活着！绝对地
I'm gonna live. Live my life to the end.
I wanna be absolutely alive! Absolutely!
弗雷亚。。。
Freyja...
我也想和你一起生活，弗雷弗雷！
I wanna live life together
with you too, Fre-Fre!
对让我们一起生活。
Yes. Let's live life, together.
没有别的办法了。Walkure必须是我们五个人。
There's no other way. Walkure
absolutely has to be all five of us.
我也想生活。
I want to live life too.
Mikumo、Makina、Reina和Freyja。
Mikumo, Makina, Reina, and Freyja.
我非常想和你们一起活到最后！
I absolutely want to live to the
very end, together with all of you!
卡奈姆。。。
Kaname...
好吧让我们唱歌！
Alright! Let's sing!
我们的生命之歌！绝对地
Our life's song! Absolutely!
Mikumo…你说对了！
Mikumo... You betcha!
为了银河系。
For the galaxy.
对于外面的人。
For someone out there.
我们打算。。。
We are going to...
全力以赴。
Give it all we've got.
尽情享受吧，就像这是我们最后一次一样！
Enjoy it as though it's our last!
去Walkure！步行！
Go! Walkure!
不会放弃，不会放弃，
不会放弃，
Won't give up, won't give up,
won't give up,
永远不会
never ever
不
No!
让我们一起生活吧，Freyja！
Let's live life together, Freyja!
海亚特！
Hayate!
我会保护你Freyja。
I'll protect you Freyja.
我们保护Walkire！这就是Delta Flight所做的！
We protect Walkire! That's
what Delta Flight does!
飞吧，海亚特！我会唱歌！
Fly, Hayate! I'll sing!
现在，现在，现在
Now, now, now, [ can hear someone's voice
歌声，歌声，歌曲，我被星辰的牵引所指引。苹果园。
Songs, songs, songs, I'm guided by the pull
of the stars Winderemere. The apple orchards.
歌曲，歌曲，歌曲
Songs, songs, songs, I'm guided
by the pull of the stars
歌曲、歌曲、歌曲，我被明星的吸引力所引导，我们自己绝对要把他们夺回！
Songs, songs, songs, I'm guided by the pull of the
stars We're absolutely taking them back ourselves!
放飞那神秘的声音
（飞向天空）
Let fly that mysterious sound
(fly to the sky)
让那神秘的声音飞向天空，三角洲飞行，我们走！
Let fly that mysterious sound (fly
to the sky) Delta Flight, let's go!
放飞那神秘的声音
（飞向天空）
Let fly that mysterious sound
(fly to the sky)
让那神秘的声音飞起来（飞到天空）——达！\噢，先生！
Let fly that mysterious sound (fly to the sky) - Da!
- Oorah sir!
-噢，先生！
-Da/
- Da/
- Oorah sir!
我想把它们送到宇宙（飞向星星）-达！\噢，先生！
I want to send them to the cosmos (fly to the stars) - Da!
- Oorah sir!
!/ 想把它们送到宇宙中去（飞向星星）
!/ want to send them to the cosmos
(fly to the stars)
一首与我渴望的光相吻合的旋律
A melody that aligns with
the light I yearn for
耶耶耶耶
Yeah yeah yeah
噢，高贵的心，发出你的诞生之声（唤醒）。瓦尔库的生物折叠波正在迅速增加。
Oh noble heart, let out your birth cry (awaken)
Walkure's Bio-Fold Waves are increasing rapidly.
哦，高贵的心，发出你的诞生之声
（觉醒）
Oh noble heart, let out your birth cry
(awaken)
哦，高贵的心，让你的出生哭泣（醒来），这样他们仍然可以歌唱。
Oh noble heart, let out your birth
cry (awaken) So they can still sing.
所以他们仍然可以唱歌。
So they can still sing.
一起唱歌，在时代变迁中，他们还能唱歌。
Sing together, amidst changing times
So they can still sing.
在瞬息万变的时代里，一起歌唱
Sing together, amidst changing times
在瞬息万变的时代里，一起歌唱的确是M女士自己选择的一种强大的音乐武器。
Sing together, amidst changing times Indeed a
formidable musical weapon, chosen by Lady M herself.
在瞬息万变的时代里，一起歌唱
Sing together, amidst changing times
在不断变化的时代里，一起唱歌，赛伦对他们进行了研究。
It was beneficial that Siren studied them.
Siren研究它们是有益的。
嚎叫！决心/还没有，还没有，尚未，还没有！Siren研究它们是有益的。
A howl! of determination/ Not yet, not yet, not yet,
not yet! It was beneficial that Siren studied them.
嚎叫！决心的决心/还没有，还没有，尚未，尚未！
A howl! of determination/
Not yet, not yet, not yet, not yet!
不会放弃，不会让步，
Won't give up, won't give an inch,
没有实现，爱在哭泣
unfulfilled, love is crying
独自承受的美德？
D不需要/
The virtue of bearing it alone?
Don't need it/
心在呼唤彼此，
Hearts calling out to each other,
心在呼唤着彼此，我能看到！
I can see it!
团结起来，释放出共鸣的歌曲
Uniting to unleash a resonating song
联合起来，释放出一首共鸣的歌曲
I可以看到风！
uniting to unleash a resonating song
I can see the wind!
让我深深地感受你
Let me feel you deeply, deeply
超越时空！
beyond time and space!
不会放弃，不会放弃，
不会放弃，
Won't give up, won't give up,
won't give up,
让它变得更好
make it better
我想让它响起，
响起，响起
I want to make it ring out,
ring out, ring out
! 想让它响起，
响起，响起，我跟不上了！
! want to make it ring out,
ring out, ring out I can't keep up!
我跟不上了！
I can't keep up!
没完没了
I跟不上了！
Endlessly
I can't keep up!
无休止地
Endlessly
我能看到它！
I can see it!
从这里，我看不到任何人的动作。
From here, I can see
everyone's movements.
三角洲5号，硬下潜。
Delta 5, hard dive.
三角洲6，三点钟
+35度。
Delta 6, three o'clock
plus 35 degrees.
三角洲3，十点钟
+27度，稳定。
Delta 3, ten o'clock
plus 27 degrees, steady.
什么
What?
但那里什么也没有。。。
But there's nothing there...
这是命令！准备好！
That's an order! Get ready!
编队：中卫！
Formation: Midgard!
罗杰！
Roger!
让我更伤心，让我更感受
Break me more, feel me more
更让我心碎，更让我感觉到目标？！
Target in sight?!
你在吗？你在外面吗？\我们就在他们的尾巴上/
Are you there? Are you out there?
We're right on their tails/
你在吗？你在外面吗？
Are you there? Are you out there?
你在吗？你在外面吗？\拿着这个！
Take this!
拿着这个！
战场上绽放的生命，
抓住这个！
Life that blooms on the battlefield,
Take this!
战场上绽放的生命，
Life that blooms on the battlefield,
让它燃烧，让它燃烧
let it burn, let it burn
如果我的命运即将消逝，就结束我
End me if my fate is to fade away
如果我的命运即将消逝，就干掉我！
Right on, commander!
如果我的命运即将消逝，就结束我
End me if my fate is to fade away
如果我的命运即将消逝，请终结我
T太棒了/！
End me if my fate is to fade away
That was great/!
如果我的命运即将消逝，就结束我
End me if my fate is to fade away
如果我的命运即将消逝，请终结我。你读着风！
You read the wind!
你读风！
燃烧，燃烧，在毁灭的尽头你读到了风！
Burning, burning, at the end
of destruction You read the wind!
燃烧，燃烧，在毁灭的边缘
Burning, burning, at the
end of destruction
燃烧，燃烧，在毁灭的最后……我在飞翔我自己的天空！
Burning, burning, at the end of
destruction ... I'm flying my own sky!
…我在飞翔我自己的天空！
...I'm flying my own sky!
呼唤奇迹
…我在飞翔自己的天空！
Call forth miracles
... I'm flying my own sky!
创造奇迹
Call forth miracles
在封闭的天空中
in the sealed sky
美好的幻影。
Good going Mirage.
在封闭的天空中
In the sealed sky
Gamma飞往B7区域！
in the sealed sky
Gamma Flight to area B7!
伽玛飞行到B7区域！
我现在明白了，成为领导者的天赋。
I see now, the talent to be a leader.
爱到极限，我现在明白了，成为领导者的天赋。
Love at the limit,
I see now, the talent to be a leader.
无国界危险，简直是疯了
Dangerously border less, it's just insane
但我仍在加速
Yet I'm still accelerating
但我仍在加速。你比我更适合做这把椅子。
Yet I'm still accelerating You're
better suited for the chair than I am.
但我仍在加速
Yet I'm still accelerating
I将把指挥权交给你，
I'm leaving command to you,
我把指挥权交给你，
舞得飞快，我把指挥权交给你，
Dancing swiftly,
I'm leaving command to you,
舞姿飞快，
Dancing swiftly,
跳得很快，阿拉德队长！
Captain Arad!
如果这是我的极限，继续摧毁我
If this is my limit, go ahead and destroy me
我是由
Max制造的。
I am made from
Max.
我是由
I am made from
我是天生的，我认识你很久了，
I've known you a long time,
我认识你很久了，
毁灭与重生
I认识你很久了，
destruction and rebirth
I've known you a long time,
毁灭与重生
destruction and rebirth
我认为这是你做过的最好的决定。
destruction and rebirth and I think
this is the best decision you've ever made.
让我们把它带到天空！
Let's take it to the skies!
爱在极限，
Love at the limit,
禁止的边界，
无论挑战如何
the forbidden borderline,
no matter the challenge
我会突破这一切
I'll break through it all
我要冲破这一切-真是一场大风！
-队长？
I'll break through it all - What a wind!
- Captain?
-多大的风啊！
-队长？
- What a wind!
- Captain?
飞快地跳舞，-多大的风！
-队长？
Dancing swiftly, - What a wind!
- Captain?
舞姿飞快，
Dancing swiftly,
跳得很快，我不再是队长了。
I'm no longer captain.
拉动更多的G，感官正在衰退？
Pulling even more G's, senses are fading
Huh?
拉动更多G's，感官正在衰退
Pulling even more G's, senses are fading
拉更多的G，感觉正在衰退
I只是个天才！
pulling even more G's, senses are fading
I'm just a genius!
拉动更多G's，感官正在衰退
Pulling even more G's, senses are fading
拉更多的G，感觉正在衰退这是。。。
pulling even more G's, senses are fading
This is...
我的身体失去控制了/
I要飞走了
My body is losing control/
I'm gonna fly away
我的身体失控了，我要飞走了，警报器系统检测到不规则的波形！
My body is /losing control I'm gonna fly away
Irregular wave patterns detected in the Siren System!
我的身体失去控制了/
I要飞走了
My body is losing control/
I'm gonna fly away
我的身体正在失去控制/我是
gonna fly away它在学习什么？
My body is losing control/ I'm
gonna fly away What is it learning?
我的身体失去控制了/
I要飞走了
My body is losing control/
I'm gonna fly away
我的身体失去控制/我要飞了
away Ma cross Cannon力量等级下降！
My body is losing control/ I'm gonna fly
away Ma cross Cannon power level dropping!
马十字炮威力等级下降！
Ma cross Cannon power level dropping!
达到带着爱（领先）
Ma交叉加农炮威力等级下降！
Reach! With love (lead)
Ma cross Cannon power level dropping!
跳舞（我有空！）
Dance (I'm free!)
I将立即进行调整。
I will make adjustments right away.
我会马上进行调整。
奇幻大教堂
I将立即进行调整。
Fantasy Archrium
I will make adjustments right away.
梦幻圣殿
Fantasy Archrium
梦幻大神殿
Alpha Flight，掩护Walkure！
Fantasy Archrium
Alpha Flight, cover Walkure!
Alpha Flight，掩护Walkure！
我们可以做到这一点
We can do this
Alpha Flight, cover Walkure!
当你醒来时，我会在你身边，我永远不会让你在9点30度的时候再去，加油！
When you wake, I'll be by your side, I'll never
let you go again 9 o'clock at 30 degrees, engage!
当你醒来时，我会在你身边，我再也不会让你走了
When you wake, I'll be by your side,
I'll never let you go again
当你醒来时，我会在你身边，我再也不会让你走了，爸爸！
When you wake, I'll be by your
side, I'll never let you go again Da!
当你醒来时，我会在你身边，我再也不会让你走了
When you wake, I'll be by your side,
I'll never let you go again
当你醒来时，我会在你身边，我永远不会再让你走了，白骑士……把你的风借给我！
When you wake, I'll be by your side, I'll never
let you go again White Knight... lend me your wind!
白骑士……借我你的风！
White Knight... lend me your wind!
我发誓（你的眼睛）
White Knight…借给我你的风！
I swear (Your eyes)
White Knight... lend me your wind!
白骑士……借我你的风！
耀眼（狂风）
White Knight…借我你的风！
Are dazzling (squall)
White Knight... lend me your wind!
白骑士……借我你的风！
本能的冲动，一个幽灵般的遗产
White Knight……借我你的风！
A rush of instinct, a phantom "on” legacy
White Knight... lend me your wind!
本能的冲动，虚幻的遗产
A rush of instinct, a phantom "on” legacy
寂静，永恒的空间
Silence, an everlasting space
真空振动射线
Vacuum Vibe-ray-tion
理解。
Understood.
真空振动射线
Vacuum Vibe-ray-tion
真空振动射线找回黑暗使者并逃离-
Singer of the Dark and making my escape—
Vacuum Vibe-ray-tion Retrieving the
你真傻。。。
That was foolish of you...
没有人能穿越艾司隆而活着。。。
No one crosses Epsilon and lives...
死亡
Die.
把所有的力量都交给马十字炮！
Direct all power to
the Ma cross Cannon!
但是船不能接受！
But the ship can't take it!
它可能在开火时爆炸！
It might explode upon firing!
没关系。我命令全体船员弃船。
It doesn't matter. I'm ordering
all crew to abandon ship.
海姆达尔革命将持续下去，
The Heimdall revolution will live on,
你将成为它的动力！
and you will be its driving force!
哈拯救！
Ha! Saverg!
接通强制能量充电。
Engaging forced energy charge.
上帝保佑你
God Bless You
[我从来不知道[/会如此爱某人
[I never knew [/ could love
someone this much
这种感觉永远不会
This feeling will never
-再次保持原样
-上帝保佑你
-be the same again
-God Bless You
这个世界上唯一的幸福
The only happiness in a world like this
像这样的世界上唯一的幸福就是这首优美的歌。
What a beautiful song.
这个世界上唯一的幸福
The only happiness in a world like this
像这样的世界上唯一的幸福。。。
Freyja...
弗雷亚。。。
分享我们的喜悦，
Freyja。。。
ls sharing our joy,
Freyja...
分享我们的喜悦，
ls sharing our joy,
这些恐惧的原因
the reason for these fears
A生命之风。。。
A wind of life...
这些恐惧的原因
the reason for these fears
So regal。。。
So regal...
这些恐惧的原因
the reason for these fears
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
还没有，还没有，尚未，尚未！
Not yet, not yet, not yet, not yet!
不会放弃，不会放弃，
Won't give up, won't give nothing,
敲响希望之钟
ring the bell of hope
如果我们中有人失踪，我们就不完整了？
这是不假思索的/
We're incomplete if any one of us missing?
That goes without thinking/
五条路径组成五线员工，
Five paths form a five-line staff,
要流传下来的故事
a story to pass down
把它刻在我身上，
Carve it into me, blazingly,
该死，以光速！
blazingly, at the speed of light!
人工重力系统损坏'！
Artificial gravity system damaged'!
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
三角洲6！关注强盗！
Delta 6! Focus on the bandits!
不会放弃，不会放弃，
Won't give up, won't give up,
歌曲不是幻想
Songs aren't illusions
音乐并不是幻想
Music that can connect us is no fantasy
你能听到这个声音吗？
Can you hear this voice?
你在哭吗？
Are you crying?
你在笑吗？
Are you laughing?
我将永远（在你身边）
I'll always be (at your side)
问这些问题
Asking these questions
闭上眼睛，仔细聆听你对我的记忆
Close your eyes, listen closely
to your memory of me
闭上眼睛，仔细听你对我的记忆啊，他进步了。
Close your eyes, listen closely to
your memory of me Ah, he's improved.
啊，他进步了。
Ah, he's improved.
! 希望你永远感觉到我在那里，所以不要放手/啊，他进步了。
! want you to always feel me there,
so don't let go/ Ah, he's improved.
! 希望你能一直感觉到我在那里，所以不要放手/
! want you to always feel me there,
so don't let go/
伸出双手触摸我！\看到了，我真的很温暖
Reach out with both hands and touch me!
See, I'm really warm
伸出双手触摸我！看，我真的很热情，麦克斯指挥官！
Reach out with both hands and touch
me! See, I'm really warm Commander Max!
伸出双手触摸我！\看到了，我真的很温暖
Reach out with both hands and touch me!
See, I'm really warm
伸出双手触摸我！看，我真的很热情去吧，伊梅尔曼！我支持你！
Reach out with both hands and touch me! See, I'm
really warm Go, Immelmann! I've got your back!
伸出双手触摸我！\看到了，我真的很温暖
Reach out with both hands and touch me!
See, I'm really warm
伸出双手，触摸我！看，我真的很温暖我也是！
Reach out with both hands and
touch me! See, I'm really warm Me too!
我也是！
Me too!
滔滔不绝的话，我也是！
With a shower of words,
Me too!
用一连串的话，
With a shower of words,
滔滔不绝的话语，
还有我/
With a shower of words,
And me/
用一连串的话，
With a shower of words,
用滔滔不绝的话语，
Roger！
With a shower of words,
Roger!
用一连串的话，
With a shower of words,
（你的一切）
(Your everything)
我抱着你。
I hold you.
还没有，还没有，尚未，还没有
Not yet, not yet, not yet,
not yet, not yet, not yet
还没有，还没有，尚未，还没有。。。
Not yet, not yet, not yet, not
yet, not yet, not yet Hayate...
海亚特。。。
Hayate...
不会放弃，一寸也不会放弃，
哈亚特。。。
Won't give up, won't give an inch,
Hayate...
不会放弃，不会让步，
Won't give up, won't give an inch,
没有实现，爱在哭泣
unfulfilled, love is crying
独自承受的美德？
D不需要/
The virtue of bearing it alone?
Don't need it/
独自承受的美德？
不需要/电源不足。。。
The virtue of bearing it alone?
Don't need it/ Not enough power...
独自承受的美德？
D不需要/
The virtue of bearing it alone?
Don't need it/
独自承受的美德？
不需要/Delta 5，拿着这些/
The virtue of bearing it alone?
Don't need it/ Delta 5, take these!/
心在呼唤彼此，
Hearts calling out to each other,
心在呼唤彼此，主持人？！现在那是我们的指挥官！
Ghosts?! Now that's our commander!
心在呼唤彼此，
Hearts calling out to each other,
团结起来，释放出共鸣的歌曲
uniting to unleash a resonating song
让我深深地感受你，
Let me feel you deeply,
深度，超越时间和空间！
deeply, beyond time and space!
我们走吧！
Deeply, beyond time and space!
Here we go!
深度，超越时间和空间！
Deeply, beyond time and space!
不会放弃，不会放弃，
不会放弃，
Won't give up, won't give up,
won't give up,
只是想。。。
Just wanna...
看透它，看透它，
See it through, see it through,
see it through,
直到最后
to the very end
海亚特！
Hayate!
去
Go!
去抓他们/
Go get 'em/
向前地
Forward!
再多一点！
Just a little more!
“一个绿色的水果就是一个
"A fruit still green is one
被吸引是二
Being attracted is two
我的心在燃烧”
My heart is burning”
歌声重叠
The sound of singing overlaps
带着遥远的回忆
with distant memories
Freyja！
Freyja!
那是。。。
That's...
传奇之歌！
The song of legend!
我走的路和我来的路
The way I'm going and the way I came
两者都没有错误
There are no mistakes in either
因为我很开心和满足（ha-）
Because I am happy and content (ha-)
让我们唱一首祈祷歌
Let us sing a song of prayer, that it
到达遥远的海岸
reaches the far shores
of this sea of light
要实现的梦想，我生命之火燃烧
A dream to fulfill,
the fire of my life burns
让我们通过音乐来表达活着的喜悦
Let us express through music
the joy of being alive
我爱你
I love you
我们交易的话升天了
The words we trade rise to the heavens
低沉的旋律
A murmured melody
低语的旋律
I能听到！每个人都在唱歌。
A murmured melody
I can hear it! Everyone's singing.
我能听到！每个人都在唱歌。
在我内心深处
Somewhere deep within me
它最终会变成一个星系
it becomes a galaxy, eventually
欢乐和悲伤
Joy and sorrow
欢乐和悲伤\花。。。
Flowers...
欢乐和悲伤
Joy and sorrow
欢乐和悲伤这是。。。
This is...
欢乐和悲伤
Joy and sorrow
给他们注入生命，让他们变得充实…传奇。。。
breathe life into them so they become full
...The legendary...
给他们注入生命，让他们变得充实
breathe life into them so they become full
给他们注入生命，让他们变得充实。。。符文花。。。
...Rune Flower...
给他们注入生命，让他们变得充实
breathe life into them so they become full
仿佛在歌唱（ha-）
As if in song (ha-)
让那温柔的梦想
Let that tender dream
你把你的心戒指拿出来
you hold in your heart ring out
你把戒指放在心里不放，天哪！
Oh my gosh!
你把你的心戒指拿出来
You hold in your heart ring out
Yami_Q_天，他们是。。。！
you hold in your heart ring out
Yami_Q_ray, they're...!
你把你的心戒指拿出来
You hold in your heart ring out
你在心里唱着我们的歌！
you hold in your heart ring out
singing our song!
你把你的心戒指拿出来
You hold in your heart ring out
充满爱，我的身体燃烧
Full of love, my body burns
我赞扬这种温暖
I commend this warmth
走向新的未来
to a new future
迈向新的未来
Freyja！
to a new future
Freyja!
走向新的未来
To a new future
迈向新的未来
Let’s fly together！
to a new future
Let's fly together!
走向新的未来
To a new future
迈向新的未来-我们走！
-我们走！
to a new future - Let's go!
- Let's go!
让我们唱一首祈祷歌
Let us sing a song of prayer, that it
到达遥远的海岸
reaches the far shores
of this sea of light
要实现的梦想，我生命之火燃烧
A dream to fulfill,
the fire of my life burns
一个要实现的梦想，我生命中的火焰燃烧着唤醒。。。
A dream to fulfill, the fire
of my life burns To wake...
要实现的梦想，我生命之火燃烧
A dream to fulfill,
the fire of my life burns
一个要实现的梦想，我生命的火焰燃烧着银河！
A dream to fulfill, the fire
of my life burns he galaxy!
要实现的梦想，我生命之火燃烧
A dream to fulfill,
the fire of my life burns
所有船只，开火！
All ships, fire!
海亚特！
Hayate!
海亚特。。。
Hayate...
…你把你的心戒指拿出来
...you hold in your heart ring out
充满爱，我的身体燃烧
Full of love, my body burns
我赞扬这种温暖。。。
I commend this warmth
Hayate...
我赞扬这种温暖
I commend this warmth
我赞扬这种温暖。。。
Son of a...
我赞扬这种温暖
I commend this warmth
为了一个新的未来，“所有的风都将合而为一。”
to a new future
So, "all winds will be as one."
走向新的未来
To a new future
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
从我的心底
From the bottom of my heart
我爱你
I love you
-弗雷亚！
-Freyja！
- Freyja!
弗雷娅…弗雷娅。
Freyja... Freyja.
弗雷亚。。。
Freyja...
海亚特。。。
Hayate...
所以这个婴儿是。。。
So this baby is...
是的……你用你的歌拯救了生命。
Yeah... a life you saved with your song.
哦，它在移动。
Oh, it's moving.
我不相信。。。
I don't believe it...
哦……一个符文。这是一个符文。
Oh... a rune. It's a rune.
非常感谢。谢谢你，海亚特。
Thank you. Thank you, Hayate.
是的……谢谢你，弗雷娅。
Yeah... thank you, Freyja.
你的歌唱感觉很好。
As始终。
Your singing felt pretty good.
As always.
海亚特的伊梅尔曼舞也是……非常的歌里·戈里。
Hayate's Immelmann Dance
was... very Gori-Gori too.
充满爱，我的身体燃烧
Full of love, my body burns
充满爱，我的身体燃烧着？
Singing?
充满爱，我的身体燃烧
Full of love, my body burns
充满爱，我的身体燃烧着\花…每个人的符文花
Flowers... Everyone's Rune Flowers
花…每个人的符文花
我赞扬这种温暖
Flowers…Everyone’s Rune Flowers
I commend this warmth
Flowers... Everyone's Rune Flowers
我赞扬这种温暖
I commend this warmth
are盛开。
are blooming.
走向新的未来
To a new future
它太美了…看起来就像盛开的苹果花。
It's so beautiful... looks just
like apple blossoms in bloom.
是的…太美了。
Yes... so beautiful.
花是白色的。
Flowers are white.
苹果是红色的。
Apples are red.
绿色的时候是酸的。
They're sour when they're green.
它们成熟时很甜。
They're sweet when they're ripe.
Gori甜。Gori很好吃。
Gori-sweet. Gori-tasty.
是的，他们很可爱。Gori很好吃。
Yeah, they're Gori-sweet. Gori-tasty.
Mercats很可爱。
Mercats are cute.
水母可以发光并漂浮在空中。
Jellyfish can glow and float in the sky.
孤独是孤独的。
Being alone is lonely.
和每个人在一起感觉很。。。
Being with everyone feels so...
-有趣。
-温暖。
- Fun.
- Warm.
夕阳的紫色色调。
The purple hue of a sunset.
鸟儿的啁啾声。
The chirping of birds.
醒来的味道。
The smell of waking up.
雪地。
The snowy land.
风是柔和的。
The wind is gentle.
唱歌很有趣。
Singing is fun.
海亚特。。。
Hayate...
我爱你，海亚特。
I love you, Hayate.
我爱你，弗雷娅。
I love you, Freyja.
谢谢你，弗雷弗雷。。。
Thank you, Fre-Fre...
我们永远在一起，绝对。。。
We'll always be together, absolutely...
没错，我们是瓦尔库尔。\我们五岁，我们一岁。
That's right, we are Walkure.
We are five and we are one.
让我们继续唱生命之歌。
Let's continue to sing the song of life.
单词
The words
渗透到我的
seeping through my
干裂的嘴唇
parched lips
消散到稀薄的空气中
dissipate into thin air
捡起我的破碎，
Picking up my broken,
空壳
empty shell
它让我
It makes me
想听听你的声音
want to hear your voice
当我仰望开阔的天空
When I look up at the open sky
我的腿开始了
My legs start
再次摇晃
shaking again
尽管我想相信
Even though I want to believe
这个世界上的一切都有意义
that everything in this world has meaning
我还没决定，
My mind undecided,
我继续我的旅程
I continue my journey
但这个疑问正好证明了
But this doubt just proves
我仍然
that I'm still
今天还活着
alive today
哈哈哈哈
Huh Huh Huh
耶耶耶耶
Yeah Yeah Yeah
是的是的
Yeah Yeah
哈哈哈哈
Huh Huh Huh
耶耶耶耶
Yeah Yeah Yeah
是的是的
Yeah Yeah
我自私吗？我是不是太淘气了？
Am I selfish? Am I being naughty?
我只是不想失去你
I just don't wanna lose you
一点一点，时间很慢
Bit by bit, time is slowly
耗尽
running out
当你觉得这样的时候，抬起你的下巴
When you feel like this, hold your chin up
我们必须为战争而行动，对吗？
We have to move for war a, right?
我准备好了
I'm ready
这么一个纯洁疯狂的宝宝
Such a pure and crazy BABY
这么一个傲慢又听话的孩子
Such an arrogant and obedient BABY
有点像被禁止的苹果。
所有的。。。
Kinda like the forbidden apple.
Everything's...
哦是的
OH YEAH
大胆的拥抱很酷
Bold embraces are cool
伟大的结局很酷
Great endings are cool
1、2、123通/
1, 2, 123 GO/
爱可以去BAN BAN BA BA BAN
Love can go BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
带上符文的布鲁姆
and take bloom in a rune
（呼呼）
(Hu Huh)
倾盆大雨可以拥抱
Pouring rains can hug
整个星球都很接近
an entire planet close
哇哇哇（Huh）
WOH WOH WOH (Huh)
我们走吧BAN BAN BAB BAN
Let's go BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
培育这个符文，让它绽放
to nurture this rune and let it bloom
感觉你在那里
By feeling you there
BAN BAN公司
BAN BAN
请不要忘记
Please don't forget
爱可以去BAN BAN BA BA BAN
Love can go BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
并在符文中绽放（胡呼）
and take bloom in a rune (Hu Huh)
即使梦想终有一天会结束
Even if it's a dream that will end one day
没关系，
Doesn't matter,
!/ 爱你（哼）
!/ love you (Huh)
我们走吧BAN BAN BAB BAN
Let's go BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
让这个符文在未来绽放
to make this rune bloom
in the times to come
直到我们再次见面
Until the day we meet again
班班班班
BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
符文·皮卡！（哼）
Rune Pika! (Huh)
班班班班
BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
符文·皮卡！（哼）
Rune Pika! (Huh)
班班班班
BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
符文·皮卡！（哼）
Rune Pika! (Huh)
花是白色的。
Flowers are white.
它们的气味温和。
Their scent is mild.
太阳很亮。
The sun is shiny.
符文也很闪亮。
Runes are shiny too.
海亚特飞。
Hayate flies.
弗雷亚唱歌。
Freyja sings.
我也唱歌！
I sing too!
呵呵，“我马上就来！”
Hehe, “I'm comin' right atcha!"